好的 让我们再来最后一次
All right, let's do this one last time.
《蜘蛛侠的真实生活故事》
对应1995年出版的《蜘蛛侠的秘密故事》
我是彼得帕克
My name is Peter Parker.
大家好 我的名字叫彼得·帕克
我被一只基因改造过的蜘蛛咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
这十年以来
And for 10 years...
我一直都在当
I've been the one
独一无二的
and only
蜘蛛侠
Spider- Man.
相信你们都在知道剩下的故事
I'm pretty sure you know the rest.
能力越大 责任越大
With great power comes great responsibility.
我拯救了很多人 坠入了爱河 拯救过这个城市
I saved a bunch of people, fell in love, saved the city.
然后我又拯救了这个城市
And then I saved the city again.
一次又一次
And again and again
又一次
and again.
然后我还
And I did, uh...
这样了
I did this.
♪ Get on up Get yourself together ♪
♪ Drive that funky soul ♪
虽然我们不怎么提及这件事
We don't really talk about this.
《蜘蛛侠的真实生活故事》
我出现在漫画书封面上 燕麦片的盒子上
Look, I'm a comic book. I'm a cereal.
还出过一个圣诞歌曲专辑
Did a Christmas album.
还拥有一个很酷的主题曲
I have an excellent theme song.
蜘蛛侠
动画及主题曲来自六十年代的蜘蛛侠动画片
♪ Spider- man Spider- man ♪
还有这个不怎么样的冰棒
And a so- so popsicle.
也有过很辛苦的时候
I mean, I've looked worse.
不过不管怎么说
But after everything...
我热爱着蜘蛛侠这个身份
I still love being Spider- Man.
不过 谁不会呢
I mean, who wouldn't?
所以不管我被打倒多少次
So no matter how many hits I take...
我永远都会想办法振作起来
...I always find a way to come back.
因为只有我才能阻挡
Because the only thing standing between this city and oblivion
这个城市遭到毁灭
is me.
这个世界上只有一个蜘蛛侠
There's only one Spider- Man.
而他就在你面前
And you're lookin' at him.
♪ Needless to say... ♪
♪ Nevertheless Callin' it quits ♪
- 迈尔斯 Miles! - ♪ Now, baby, I'm a wreck ♪
- 迈尔斯 Miles!
迈尔斯 准备去上学了
Miles, papá, time for school!
迈尔斯
Miles!
- 迈尔斯 - 怎么了
- Miles! - Yeah! Yeah?
你书包收拾好了没 要去学校了
Are you finished packing for school?
收拾好了
Yeah.
我熨完剩下的几件衣服就好了
Just ironing my last shirt.
♪ You're a sunflower... ♪
好了 你现在都长这么大了
Come on! You a grown man now.
- 要把你最精神的一面展现给老师们 - 迈尔斯
- Let's show these teachers that. - Miles!
我的电脑在哪里
Where's my laptop?
如果你想搭顺风车的话 我们最好现在就出发了
If you want me to drive you, we gotta go now.
不用了 爸爸 我自己走路就行了
No, Dad, I'll walk.
- 我可是你的司机哟 - 没事的
- Personal chauffeur going once. - It's okay.
- 迈尔斯 要走了 - 再给我一分钟
- Miles! Gotta go. - In a minute!
- 要出发了 再给我一分钟
- Gotta go. - In a minute!
妈妈 我要出发了
Mom, I gotta go.
再给我一分钟
In a minute.
周五见
See you Friday.
你来了啊 兄弟 近来如何
Look who's back. Yo, what's going on, bro?
你好啊 路过而已 我很好
Hey, I'm just walking by. How you doin'?
嘿 迈尔斯 你有感受到昨晚的地震吗
Yo, Miles! You feel that earthquake last night?
你在说什么 我昨天晚上睡的很熟
What you talkin' about? I slept like a baby last night.
- 迈尔斯你的新学校怎么样啊 - 蛮好的
- How's that new school? - So easy.
- 我很想你 迈尔斯 - 你在说什么 我还住在这里啊
- We miss you, Miles. - You miss me? I still live here!
等等 你说你想我
Wait, you miss me?
哎呦
Contra!
呃不是吧
Oh, come on.
说真的 我完全可以自己走过去的
Seriously, Dad. Walking would've been fine.
等星期六的时候 你有的是机会走路
You can walk plenty on Saturday
你边走边把你之前贴的贴纸撕下来
when you peel those stickers off.
你看到了 我都不知道那些是不是我贴的耶
You saw that? I don't know if that was me.
还有昨天在克林顿路的那两张
And the two from yesterday on Clinton.
好吧 那是我贴的
Yeah, those were me.
所以 你看那家新开的咖啡店
Look at that. Another new coffee shop.
- 你看到了么 - 看到了
- You see that? - Totally. Yeah.
- 那个店名是啥啊 - 泡沫派对
- What's that one called? - Foam Party.
泡沫派对 好吧
"Foam Party"? Come on.
你看到了那里没 排了很长的队
And everyone is just linin' up. You see that?
看到了
I see it.
都不知道是个咖啡店还是个舞厅了
Is that a coffee shop or a disco?
爸爸 你老了
Dad, you're old, man.
已收到多次报告
There are multiple reports
昨晚又发生一起神秘地震事件
of another mysterious seismic event last night.
有熟悉蜘蛛侠情况的消息人士表示 蜘蛛侠会展开调查
Sources close to Spider- Man say he's looking into the problem.
蜘蛛侠 每天就在外面
Spider- Man. I mean, this guy swings in once a day,
戴着面罩荡来荡去 无视法律
zip- zap- zop in his little mask and answers to no one. Right?
是的 爸爸 没错
Yeah, Dad. Yeah.
然后 我的同事都在外面
Meanwhile, my guys are out there,
- 是啊 - 拼死拼活 没有面罩
- lives on the line, no masks. - Uh- huh.
- 我们都是光明正大的 - 爸爸你加速 我认识这些人
- We show our faces. - Speed up. I know these kids.
- 能力越大 负担越大 With great ability comes great accountability.
- 原句是"能力越大 责任越大"
原话不是这样说的爸爸
That's not even how the saying goes.
不过我得说 蜘蛛侠牌的麦片确实很不错
I do like his cereal, though. I'll give him that.
我的天啊 警察不闯红灯的吗
Oh, my gosh. Don't cops run red lights?
有些会 但是你爸爸我不会
Oh, yeah, some do. But not your dad.
♪ My memories keep begging ♪
♪ For someone else ♪
♪ I know this feeling, yes I know it very well ♪
远景学院
为什么我不能回布鲁克林中学
Why can't I go back to Brooklyn Middle?
你只在这里上了两个星期的学
You've given it two weeks.
我们别再说这个话题了
We're not having this conversation.
我只是觉得这个学校搞得是精英主义
I just think that this new school is elitist.
- 精英主义 - 我更愿意在一个普通的学校
- "Elitist"? - And I would prefer to be
跟正常人在一起
at a normal school among the people.
正常人 这些都是正常人
"The people"? These are your people.
我之所以能在这里 完全是因为运气好
I'm only here 'cause I won that stupid lottery.
瞎扯 你和别人一样都是通过了入学考试的 好吗
No way. You passed the entry test just like everybody else.
你面前摆着这么好的一个机会 你要毁了它吗
You have an opportunity here. You wanna blow that?
你想像你叔叔一样吗
You wanna end up like your uncle?
艾伦叔叔怎么了 他是个很好的人
What's wrong with Uncle Aaron? He's a good guy.
每个人都有自己的选择
We all make choices in life.
我不觉得自己有得选
It doesn't feel like I have a choice right now.
你确实没有
You don't!
迈尔斯 我爱你
I love you, Miles.
我知道 爸爸 周五见
Yeah, I know, Dad. See you Friday.
- 你也要对我说 我爱你 爸爸 - 老爸你认真的吗
- You gotta say "I love you" back. - Dad, are you serious?
我想听你说 "我爱你 爸爸"
I wanna hear it. "I love you, Dad."
你真要我说
You wanna hear me say it?
这可是学校门口
You're dropping me off at a school.
- 我爱你 爸爸 - 你看看周围
- "I love you, Dad." - Look at this place.
爸爸我爱你
"Dad, I love you."
爸爸 我爱你
Dad, I love you.
收到
That's a copy.
把你的鞋带系好
Tie your shoes, please.
爸爸 我爱你
"I love you, Dad."
嘿 早上好 你好吗
Hey, good morning. How you doin'?
- 周末真是太短了 - 收到 哈哈
- Weekend was short, huh? - "That's a copy."
我的天 真是太尴尬了
Oh, my gosh! This is embarrassing.
我们的外套是同款耶
We wore the same jacket.
嘿 你鞋带没系好
Hey. Your shoe's untied.
对 我知道 我是故意的
Yeah, I'm aware. It's a choice.
♪ Theory is that All matter is composed ♪
♪ Of at least three ♪
♪ Fundamental particles ♪
谁能解出这题
Who can solve this for XY?
这就是所谓的 演绎推理
And that is known as a syllogism.
读《远大前程》前两章
Read two chapters of Great Expectations.
《远大前程》
这里是课后测验 考察体积 压力
A take- home quiz on volumetric pressure.
写五页论文 结论部分是 重点
Five- page essay with your conclusions stressed.
数不清的各种可能
...countless other possibilities.
可能在另一个宇宙中 我穿的衣服是红色的
There could be a universe where I am wearing red.
或者穿的是皮裤
Or wearing leather pants.
在黑暗中偷偷溜进来的莫赖斯先生 你又迟到了
Mr. Morales. Movin' in the dark. You're late again.
炼金术公司 首席科学家 奥利维亚博士
爱因斯坦说过 时间是相对的 不是吗
Einstein said time was relative, right?
或许我没有迟到 只是你们早到了而已
Maybe I'm not late. Maybe you guys are early.
抱歉 我只是觉得太安静了
Sorry. It was just so quiet.
你是想继续站着呢
Would you like to keep standing there,
还是找个位子坐下
or do you wanna sit down?
我们所处的宇宙 其实是多个平行宇宙中的一个
Our universe is, in fact, one of many parallel universes
而这些平行宇宙是在同时进行的
happening at the exact same time.
多亏了菲克斯家族研究基金会的所有人
Thanks to everyone here at the Fisk Family Foundation...
- 我喜欢你的笑话 - 真的吗
- I liked your joke. - Really?
其实并不好笑 所以我才会笑的
I mean, it wasn't funny. That's why I laughed.
不过想法挺不错的 所以我还蛮喜欢
But it was smart, so I liked it.
我之前
I don't think
好像没有见到过你
I've seen you before.
我们所做出的每个选择
Every choice that we make
都会带来无穷的可能性
would create countless other possibilities.
一个选择 带来无穷无尽的结果
A what- if to infinity.
零分吗 我再多拿几个零分的话
A zero? A few more of those,
你们大概就要把我踢出学校了吧
you'd probably have to kick me outta here, huh?
或者我只是不适合这所学校
Maybe I'm just not right for this school.
如果一个人闭着眼睛
If a person wearing a blindfold picked the answers
在一堆判断题里随便乱选
on a true- or- false quiz at random,
你觉得准确率会是多少
do you know what score they would get?
- 百分之五十 - 回答正确
- 50%? - That's right!
能避开所有正确答案
The only way to get all the answers wrong
那就证明你其实全部都会
is to know which answers are right.
你想故意被开除
You're trying to quit.
而我是不会允许的
And I'm not gonna let you.
我要罚你写一篇关于自己的文章
I'm assigning you a personal essay.
我的远大前程
不是关于物理 而是关于你自己的
Not about physics, but about you,
你想成为一个什么样的人
and what kind of person you want to be.
♪ Come on ♪
♪ Ha, sicker than Your average ♪
♪ Poppa twist cabbage Off instinct ♪
♪ Don't think ♪
♪ My Detroit players, timbs for My hooligans in Brooklyn ♪
♪ Dead right, if the head Right, Biggie there e'rynight ♪
迈尔斯
♪ Never lose, never choose to Bruise crews who ♪
我在观察你呢
- ♪ Do something to us... ♪ - ♪ Come on ♪
艾伦叔叔 嘿 吓了你一跳吧
Uncle Aaron! Hey! Were you scared?
想领教一下吗
You want that?
学校怎么样啊
What's up with school?
好的不行 交了一大堆朋友
Going great! Got tons of friends.
总不见得那里的生活糟透了吧
You can't tell me it's all that bad there.
会有迷人的聪明姑娘
Smart girls is where it's at.
那里应该有一大堆吧
Place must be full of 'em.
不 根本没有 没有这回事
No, there's no one.
做我的侄子
Yo, I can't have no nephew of mine
不至于这么不受欢迎
on the streets with no game.
谁说我没戏了 有个新来的姑娘
Hey, I got game. There's a new girl.
她其实还蛮喜欢我的
Actually, you know, she's kinda into me.
你懂的
You know how it is.
她叫什么啊
What's her name?
我们还在建立感情的阶段
You know, we layin' down the groundwork right now.
你知道搭肩膀这招吗
You know about the shoulder touch?
当然知道啊
'Course I do.
不过 你说来听听吧
But tell me anyway.
你明天去找那姑娘 走到她面前 然后
Tomorrow, find that girl. You walk up to her and be like:
嘿
"Hey."
你认真的吗 艾伦叔叔
You serious, Uncle Aaron?
我跟你说这招很有技术含量的
I'm tellin' you, man, it's science.
所以走到她面前 然后说 嘿
So walk up to her and be like: "Hey."
不不不 应该是 嘿
No, no, no, no. Like: "Hey."
嘿
"Hey."
不 嘿
No. "Hey."
嘿
"Hey."
你真的是我亲侄子吗
You sure you my nephew, man?
爸:作业做完了?
是她吗
Is that her?
我该走了 还有一篇论文要写
I should probably go. Still got a paper to do tonight.
你居然不给我看你的新作 你画到墙上了吗
Yo, you been holdin' out on me? You throw these up yet?
不别提了 你也知道我老爸 没戏的
Naw, man. You know my dad. I can't.
来吧 我带你去个好地方
Come on. I got a spot you ain't gon' believe.
不 不行不行
Naw, I can't. I can't. Can't.
我会惹上大麻烦的
I'm gonna get in so much trouble.
别怕 告诉你爸是你美术老师让你画的
Hey, man. Tell him your art teacher made you.
违禁区域 只允许授权人员进入
嘿 你怎么会知道这个地方的
How'd you know about this place?
我在这里做过工程
Did an engineering job down here.
♪ One, two, three Four, five... ♪
怎么了
What's up?
好吧 看来你真的是我亲侄子
Yeah, man, I knew we were related.
哇
Whoa!
布鲁克林
Brooklyn!
墙上有很多画
There's a lot of history on these walls.
这地方太酷了
This is so fresh.
现在看你的了迈尔斯
And now you on your own, Miles.
悠着点
Whoa, slow down a little.
很好 不错
That's better.
♪ Who's the black sheep? What's the black sheep? ♪
炼金术公司 42号蜘蛛
♪ Don't know who I am When I'm coming so you sleep ♪
看到没有 画错也是成功的一步
See what you got now? Makin' mistakes is part of it.
♪ And you can't beat that... ♪
咱们迈尔斯家的人就该这样
The real Miles comin' outta hidin'.
♪ You gotta hay? It's for the hoes ♪
现在你换种颜色的颜料 开始勾线
Now you can cut that line with another color.
♪ You can get with this Or you can get with that ♪
♪ You can get with this or You can get with that ♪
♪ I think you'll get with this For this is where it's at ♪
帮个忙
Little help?
♪ ...who was quite contrary Talkin' 'bout Mary... ♪
想要滴墨效果吗 这样也挺酷的
Did you want drips? 'Cause if you do, that's cool,
但如果不要的话 你动作得快点
but if you don't, you gotta keep it moving.
要的就是这种效果
That's intentional.
远大前程
- 哇 - 是不是太疯狂了
- Wow. - Is it too crazy?
不会
No, man.
我知道你想表达什么
Miles, I see exactly what you're doing there.
没错
Yeah. You know,
我和你爸以前也经常这么干
me and your dad used to do this back in the day.
- 别骗人了 - 是真的
- Stop lyin'. - It's true.
但有天他当了警察
Then he took on the cop thing, and I don't know...
怎么说呢 他是个好人 只是
He's a good guy, just...
你懂我意思
You know what I'm sayin'.
好了走吧伙计 我还有事
All right, come on, man. I gotta roll.
迈尔斯 快走
Miles, let's go.
好奇怪啊
That's weird.
我的裤子变短了
My pants shrank.
我想我可能发育了
I think I hit puberty.
我不应该说出来的
我得买新裤子了
I gotta get new pants.
等等 为什么我脑子里的声音这么大
Wait. Why is the voice in my head so loud?
什么
What?
- 你没事吧 - 什么
- Oh! Are you okay? - What?
我为什么会出这么多汗
Why am I so sweaty?
你怎么出这么多汗
Why are you so sweaty?
因为我在发育
It's a puberty thing.
我也不知道我为什么会这么说 我没有在发育
I don't know why I said that. I'm not going through puberty.
我是说我已经发育完了
I did, but I'm done.
我现在是个男人了
I'm a man.
你也是新来的 对吧 这点我们一样
So you're, like, new here, right? We got that in common.
没错 是这样
Yeah. That's one thing.
真棒 对了 我叫迈尔斯
Cool. Yeah. I'm Miles.
我叫格温达
I'm Gwe... anda.
等等 你叫格温达
Wait, your name is Gwanda?
对 这是个非洲人的名字 我是南非人
Yes, it's African. I'm South African.
我从小在这儿长大的 所以没有口音
No accent though 'cause I was raised here.
趁她还没走的时候快使出搭肩膀那招
Do the shoulder touch now before she walks away.
为什么这种感觉这么可怕
Why is this so scary?
是我在做慢动作 还是其实就是这种感觉
Am I doing this in slow motion or does it just feel that way?
我开玩笑的 我叫温达 没有格 开个玩笑而已
I'm kidding. It's Wanda. No "G." That's crazy. Heh.
嘿
Hey.
好吧 那么
Okay, then.
我们回头见
I'll see you around.
回见
Oh. See you.
- 抱歉 这个 - 嘿
- Sorry. Um... - Hey.
- 糟了 - 你可以放手吗
- Oh, crap. - Can you let go, please?
- 我做不到 - 啊好痛 放松 没关系
- I can't let go. - Ow! Ow! Calm down. It's fine.
- 迈尔斯 放手 - 我在想办法
- Miles, let go. - Workin' on it.
这都要怪青春期
It's just puberty.
我想你对青春期有些误解 你放松就好
I don't think you know what puberty is. Just relax.
- 好了 我有个主意 - 好极了
- Okay, I have a plan. - Great.
- 我要使劲扯了 - 这是个很糟糕的主意
- I'm gonna pull really hard. - That's a terrible plan.
- 一 - 别这么做
- One. - Don't do this.
- 二 - 三
- Two. - Three!
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you?
好的 特别高兴
Sure. Total pleasure.
没人看到 没关系的
No one saw. It's okay.
没人知道 没人知道
No one knows, no one knows.
大家都知道了
Everyone knows.
大家都知道了 他们都在嘲笑我
Everyone knows. They're talkin' 'bout me.
他们都看到了
They saw everything!
他知道了 她知道了 他们都知道了
He knows. She knows. They know.
哇她长得可真高
Wow, she's super tall.
他在笑什么 我现在是个怪胎了吗
Why is he smiling? Am I the weird guy now?
我在干什么
What am I doing?
这家伙真是个怪胎
That guy's such a weirdo.
我要怎么停下来
How do I stop?
他们能听到我在想什么
Can they hear my thoughts?!
我脑海中的声音怎么这么大声
Why are all my thoughts so loud?!
嘿 我知道你昨晚偷偷溜出去了 莫拉莱斯
Hey! I know you snuck out last night, Morales.
装傻
Play dumb!
谁是莫拉莱斯
Who's Morales?
也别那么傻吧
Not that dumb!
嘿
Hey!
好了 好了 没事了
Okay, okay. You're okay.
没事了
You're okay.
安保主管
他找不到你的
He'll never find you.
不是吧
No.
保安室
你在我办公室里做什么 莫拉莱斯
What are you doing in my office, Morales?!
莫拉莱斯快开门
Morales! Open up!
♪ Oh, Spider- bells Goblin smells ♪
为什么会这样
Why is this happening?
♪ Spider- buggy blew a tire ♪
我孩子很喜欢听这首歌
He's got a nice voice.
♪ Spidey- bells, Spidey- bells ♪
快开门
Open up!
不要再粘着了
Stop sticking!
千万别松开 迈尔斯
Keep sticking, Miles! Oh!
霍夫施塔特
Hofstadter is suggesting...
认为...
...is that we...
看....
...look on the...
好吧
Okay.
我的房间
My room!
《蜘蛛侠的真实生活故事》
怎么会这样
为什么会这样
"Why is this happening?"
别粘了
别再粘着了
"Please stop sticking."
拜托一定要粘紧
千万别松手
"Please keep st..."
Wait, wait, wait.
等等 怎么可能会有两个蜘蛛侠
How could there be two Spider- Men?
嘿 我开着车呢
你怎么不小心点飞
不可能会有两个蜘蛛侠啊
There can't be two Spider- Men.
有可能吗
Can there?
《两个蜘蛛侠》
对应漫画《蜘蛛双侠》
拜托 艾伦叔叔 快接电话 快接电话
Come on, Uncle Aaron, pick up. Pick up!
艾伦叔叔
我是艾伦
Yo, it's Aaron.
我要出城几天
I'm outta town for a few days.
回来再打给你 再见
I'll hit you when I'm back. Peace.
不不不不
No. No- No- No- No- No.
这不可能
It's not possible!
我只是在发育
It's just puberty.
那只是只普通的蜘蛛 我只是个正常的孩子
It's a normal spider and I'm a normal kid!
好
All right!
当晚稍晚时
迈尔斯寻找答案
我得找人倾诉一下这件事
I gotta tell someone.
爸爸
是你想多了 迈尔斯 你想多了
Okay, you're being crazy, Miles. You're being crazy.
只要找到那只蜘蛛
Find the spider.
一切就都清楚了
You'll see.
看到没 是只普通蜘蛛
It's a normal spider.
感觉简直 普通得不能再普通了
It's, like, boring how normal this spider is.
我在这
I'm right here.
为什么这种事会发生在我身上
Why is this happening to me?
慢点 我在干什么
Slow down! What am I doing?
在哪儿
Way over there.
你跟我很像
You're like me.
迈尔斯 小心
Miles. Look out.
我不想当英雄
I don't wanna be a hero.
迈尔斯
Miles.
诺曼 你听我说
Norman, listen to me.
蜘蛛侠
Spider- Man?
我不能让你打开通往另一个时空的大门
I cannot let you open a portal to another dimension.
这种事情不能发生在布鲁克林
Brooklyn is not zoned for that.
这不是我可以决定的
It's not up to me.
那是绿恶魔吗
Is that Green Goblin?!
你为什么不放弃
Why won't you quit?!
因为我不想布鲁克林被黑洞吞噬
I guess I like Brooklyn not being sucked into a black hole.
我还是先走为妙吧
I think I'm gonna go.
斯塔顿岛应该可以 反正布鲁克林不行
Staten Island, maybe. Not Brooklyn.
不 不
No! No!
什么情况
What now?
这是什么地方
What is this place?
你知道你鞋带松了吗
Did you know your shoes are untied?
- 知道 - 我穿的是连体服
- Uh- huh. - This is a onesie,
所以我不用担心这个
so I don't really have to worry about it.
我以为我是唯一的蜘蛛侠 你跟我一样
I thought I was the only one. You're like me.
我可不想
I don't wanna be.
恐怕你没有选择孩子
I don't think you have a choice, kiddo.
我能理解你的困惑 相信我
Got a lot going through your head, I'm sure.
你不会有事的 我可以帮你
You're gonna be fine. I can help you.
你等我一下 一会儿我教你几招
If you stick around, I can show you the ropes.
好的
Yeah.
我必须得赶在时空连续体崩塌前
I just need to destroy this big machine real quick
毁掉那台机器
before the space- time continuum collapses.
别走开
Don't move.
一会儿见
See you in a bit.
他是怎么做到的
How does he do that?
是在这儿吗 不是 是这儿
Is it here? No, no, it's here.
好了各位 派对结束了
All right, folks.
我每次都搞错
I always get this wrong.
不好了
Oh, boy.
徘徊者
Prowler.
伙计 我正忙着呢
Man, I was in the middle of something.
心好累
I am so tired.
你在生我气吗 我觉得你在生我的气
Are you mad at me? I feel like you're mad at me.
你就这点能耐吗
That all you got?
真恶心
Aw, so gross.
我应该上去帮他
I should go up there and help him.
开什么玩笑 这怎么可能
Who am I kidding? I should not do that.
注意 蜘蛛侠来了
Watch out. Here comes the Spider- Man.
喜欢我的新玩具吗
You like my new toy?
花了我不少钱 但是 钱财乃身外之物
Cost me a fortune, but, hey, can't take it with you, right?
你大老远跑来 就是为了观看我的实验
You came all this way. Watch the test.
这会是场超炫的灯光秀
It's a hell of a freaking light show.
你一定会喜欢的
You're gonna love this.
探针已激活
不不 别这样 快停下
No! No, don't do this! Stop!
你不知道它的威力有多大 你会害死我们的
You don't know what it can do! You'll kill us all!
我看到了多个宇宙正在开启
I see multiple dimensions opening!
三个四个五个不同的宇宙
That was three, four and five separate dimensions.
它们很不稳定 我们必须要停下来
It's unstable! We should stop.
诺曼 你一般怎么处理头部创伤的
Norm, what's your take on head trauma?
我都提醒你了朋友
I tried to warn you, pal.
警告
绿恶魔 不要 把他弄出去
Goblin, no! Get him outta there!
威尔逊 我们这是在哪
Wilson! Where are we?
真是奇怪
Really weird.
威尔逊
Wilson!
嘿 你没事吧
Hey! Are you okay?
我没事我没事 我只是需要休息一下
I'm fine, I'm fine. I'm just resting.
你能站起来吗
- Can't you get up? - Yeah.
我每次都能站起来
Yeah, I always get up.
咳嗽可能不是好兆头
The coughing's probably not a good sign.
找到他 快点
Find him. Now.
听着我们得合作 时间不多了
Listen, we gotta team up here. We don't have that much time.
只有这把重载钥匙能阻止对撞机
This override key is the only way to stop the collider.
荡过去 用这把钥匙 按下红色按钮 炸了它
Swing up there, use this key, push the button and blow it up.
你得把脸藏起来
You need to hide your face.
别告诉任何人你是谁
You don't tell anyone who you are.
谁都不能说 他能撬开任何的嘴
No one can know. He's got everyone in his pocket.
如果他再次启动机器
If he turns the machine on again,
你所知道的一切都会消失
everything you know will disappear.
你的家人 所有人
Your family, everyone.
所有人
Everyone.
答应我好吗
Promise me you'll do this.
我答应你
I promise.
去吧 毁了对撞机
Go. Destroy the collider.
我会去找你的
I'll come and find you.
不会有事的
It's gonna be okay.
墓碑
Tombstone.
实验到此结束
We're done with tests.
尽快准备好再次启动
Get that thing ready to go again. And soon.
动作快点
Run faster!
这些家伙真弱
These guys are weak.
我本来想说很高兴又见到你了 蜘蛛侠
I'd say it's nice to see you again, Spider- Man,
可惜不是
but it's not.
嘿 金并 生意怎么样
Hey, Kingpin. How's business?
很不错
Boomin'. Heh.
好吧 这样可不行
Nice. Aw, that's a no- no.
你这么做会在布鲁克林的下面掀开一个黑洞
This might open a black hole under Brooklyn.
我们不能冒这个险
It can't be worth the risk.
不是所有事情都是为了钱 蜘蛛侠
It's not always about the money, Spider- Man.
你不想知道我在里面看到了什么吗
Don't you wanna know what I saw in there?
等等
Wait.
我知道你想干嘛
I know what you're trying to do,
这么做没有用的
and it won't work.
他们已经死了
They're gone.
把尸体处理掉吧
Get rid of the body.
谁在那里
What was that?
杀了他
Kill that guy.
别粘着了
Stop sticking!
车门正在关闭 请远离车门
Stand clear of the closing doors, please.
这是涂鸦艺人搞的街头创作吧
Yeah, I think it's a Banksy.
警察 把手举起来
Police! Put your hands up!
迈尔斯 迈尔斯
Miles? Miles?
你怎么不在学校
Why aren't you at school?
怎么了 没事了 没事了
Whoa, whoa, whoa. It's okay. It's okay.
迈尔斯 出什么事了
Miles? ¿Qué te pasa?
是因为地震吗
Is it the earthquake?
我今晚能留下吗
Can I sleep here tonight?
迈尔斯 现在还没到周末呢
Miles. It's a weeknight.
你应该呆在学校的
You made a commitment to that school.
他不舒服
He's upset.
你当然能留下
Of course you can stay.
- 爸爸 - 嗯
- Dad? - Yeah.
你真的很讨厌蜘蛛侠吗
Do you really hate Spider- Man?
是吧 我是说 身为一名警察
Yeah. I mean, with a vigilante, there is...
杰弗森 亲爱的
Jeff, mi amor.
怎么了 是他问我的
What? He asked me.
你知道我对蜘蛛侠的看法的
Baby, you know how I feel about Spider- Man. Come on.
你知道他很爱你
Tú sabes que él te quiere mucho.
所以才会这么严格的 你知道的吧
That's why he's tough on you. You know that, right?
妈妈 你有没有想过离开布鲁克林
Mom, do you ever think about moving out of Brooklyn?
我们家的人从来不逃避问题 迈尔斯
Our family doesn't run from things, Miles.
对 我知道
Yeah, I know.
到底怎么回事
What's that about?
他正处于艰难期 杰夫
He's having a hard time, Jeff.
越是艰难
When it gets hard,
炼金术公司
他越是应该坚持
that's when he's gotta stick it out.
插播一条特别消息
We interrupt this broadcast for a special report.
一则悲痛的消息
Sad news tonight.
特别报道
我们的英雄蜘蛛侠 今天离开了我们
The hero known as Spider- Man has died
他的死与今天发生在布鲁克林的
after injuries related to another powerful earthquake
另一场神秘地震有关
in Brooklyn. Multiple sources are confirming
经多方消息证实彼得·帕克 26岁的研究生
that Peter Parker, a 26- year- old grad student
兼职摄影师
and part- time photographer
在近十多年中 一直扮演着蜘蛛侠的角色
operated as Spider- Man for at least a decade.
♪ I'm not runnin' Runnin', runnin' ♪
♪ No, I'm not afraid Of the fall ♪
♪ I'm not scared... ♪
他的遗孀 玛丽·简
He is survived by his wife, Mary Jane,
他的婶婶 梅·帕克
and his aunt, May Parker.
我们的英雄 蜘蛛侠 离世了
Our hero, Spider- Man, is gone.
♪ I'm not scared... ♪
我的丈夫彼得·帕克
My husband, Peter Parker,
他曾经是位普通人
was an ordinary person.
他总是说 谁都能成为面具后面的那个人
He always said it could've been anyone behind the mask.
他只是凑巧被蜘蛛咬了
He was just the kid who happened to get bit.
我会想念他的
I'm going to miss him.
斯坦的私货店 促销中
是啊
Yeah.
我们以前可是朋友
We were friends, you know.
如果不合身的话 我能来退货吗
Can I return it if it doesn't fit?
到最后
It always fits
总会合身的
eventually.
一旦售出 不退不换
这并不是他的本意
He didn't ask for his powers,
可他选择成为了蜘蛛侠
but he chose to be Spider- Man.
我最爱彼得的地方就是
My favorite thing about Peter
他让我们所有人都充满了力量
is that he made us each feel powerful.
我们每个人都有属于自己的力量
We all have powers of one kind or another.
♪ Of the dark... ♪
我们都在以自己的方式
But in our own way.
扮演着蜘蛛侠
We are all Spider- Man.
我们需要你
And we're all counting on you.
他们需要我
They're counting on me.
应该不是特指你 这只是个比喻而已
Probably not you specifically. I think it's a metaphor.
《蜘蛛侠的真实生活故事》
不能再逃避了
你必须得跳
无论有多危险 无论后果如何
彼得·帕克
抱歉 帕克先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Parker.
你给我的那把重载钥匙
That thing you gave me, that key
我可能把它弄坏了
I think I really messed it up.
我也想遵守约定
I wanna do what you asked.
我真的很想
I really do.
可是对不起
But I'm sorry.
我觉得我办不到
I'm not sure I'm the guy.
没有你 我一个人根本不行
I can't do this without you.
嘿孩子
Hey, kid.
我对他做了什么
What did I do to him?!
不
No.
你是谁
Who are you?
好吧 各位我们最后再来一次
All right, people, let's do this one last time.
《超凡蜘蛛侠》
我叫做彼得·班杰明·帕克
My name is Peter B. Parker.
大家好 我的名字叫彼得·B·帕克
我被一只基因改造过蜘蛛咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
在接下来二十二年里
And for the last 22 years,
我以为我是这个世界上唯一的蜘蛛侠
I thought I was the one and only Spider- Man.
忙碌的一天
What a day.
剩下的你们肯定都知道了
I'm pretty sure you know the rest.
我拯救过这个城市 坠入过爱河 还结了婚
You see, I saved the city, fell in love, I got married,
又救了几次城市 或许救的太多了
saved the city some more, maybe too much.
我的婚姻出现了危机 投资了一些糟糕的项目
My marriage got testy, made some dicey money choices.
《号角日报》时评 小蜘蛛餐厅太烂了
千万别投资以蜘蛛侠命名的主题餐厅
Don't invest in a spider- themed restaurant.
小蜘蛛餐厅 关门大吉
就这样过去了十五年 吧啦吧啦 超级无聊
Then like 15 years passed. Blah, blah, blah. Super boring.
我摔断了脊椎 脸撞在了无人机上
I broke my back, a drone flew into my face,
送走了梅婶婶
I buried Aunt May.
最后和我的妻子分开了
My wife and I split up.
但这一切我都沉着以对
But I handled it like a champion.
因为
'Cause, you know what,
不管遭受多少次打击
no matter how many times I get hit,
我最终总是会爬起来
I always get back up.
我有大把时间自我反省
And I got a lot of time to reflect and work on myself.
知道吗 海马一旦结合 就一辈子都不会分开
Did you know that seahorses, that they mate for life?
你能想象到这种场景么
Could you imagine?
一只海马 见到了另一只海马
A seahorse seeing another seahorse
然后他们就在一起了
and then making it work?
她想要孩子
She wanted kids and...
玛丽·简 拨号中
但是 这吓坏我了
And it scared me.
通话结束
我知道我伤了她的心
I'm pretty sure I broke her heart.
快进 当时我正在家里做俯卧撑
Flash- forward: I'm in my apartment doing push- ups,
还有仰卧起坐 让自己变得更强壮
doing ab crunches, getting strong,
突然奇怪的事情发生了
when this weird thing happened.
虽然我对奇怪的事情已经见怪不怪了
And I gotta say, weird things happen to me a lot.
可是 这次的情况真的很奇怪
But this was real weird.
我还在纽约 但是周围不太一样
You see, I was in New York, but things were different.
而且我死了
Also, I was dead.
重磅新闻 纽约市的超级英雄蜘蛛侠去世 年仅26岁
还有一头金发
And blond.
我看起来简直完美
I was kind of perfect.
感觉就像在照镜子一样
It was like looking in a mirror.
我有种直觉
I have a feeling that the thing
带我来到这儿的东西
that brought me here
就是害死他的原因
was the thing that got him killed.
想知道接下来发生了什么吗
You wanna know what happened next?
我也想知道
Me, too.
你到底是谁
Who are you?
你在那儿干些什么
What are you doin' over there?
别动 纽约警察
Freeze! P.D.N.Y.
别动
Stop!
这是在逗我吗
Are you kidding me right now?
站住 站住
Stop! Stop!
我带你走 我带你走
I gotcha. I gotcha.
嘿小子 放下尸体
Hey, kid. Drop the body.
- 嘿 小子 站住 - 站住
- Hey, kid. Get over here! - Come on, now!
回头见 警官
See you, officers!
不是吧
Aw, come on.
嘿小子 别乱动
- Hey, kid. - Kid, come on, now!
举起手来 小子
Put 'em up, son!
再见
Uh... adiós?
救命 快让火车停下
Help! Somebody stop that train!
嘿 什么鬼...
Oh, hey. What the...?
不好意思了
Sorry.
要死翘翘啦
I'm gonna die!
好像是 一个扮成蜘蛛侠的孩子
Looks like a child dressed like Spider- Man
拖着一个流浪汉的尸体在赶火车
dragging a homeless corpse behind a train.
太好了 我没有杀了你
Yes! I didn't kill you.
- 你是谁 - 你是谁
- Who are you? - Who are you?
你为什么想要杀我
Why are you trying to kill me?
我没有 我是想要救你
I'm not. I'm trying to save you.
麻烦绕道走好吗
Hey, maybe you guys can go around?
好吧 谢谢配合
All right. Thanks, New York.
那是什么
What was that?
那孩子用他的手
Kid electrocuted me
电击了我
with his hands.
- 你跟我很像啊 - 我有话要问你
- You're like me. - I got some questions.
你为什么那么像彼得·帕克
Why do you look like Peter Parker?
因为我就是彼得·帕克
Because I am Peter Parker.
那你怎么没死 头发也不一样了
Then why aren't you dead? And why is your hair different?
为什么你变老了 还有你的身材
Why are you older? And why is your body
怎么变形了
a different shape?
你只是想说我胖吧
Pretty sure you just called me fat.
你也没帅到哪里去 小子
You don't look so hot either, kid.
超级英雄不会买自己的周边
Most superheroes don't wear their own merch.
- 你是鬼魂吗 - 不是
- Are you a ghost? - No.
- 你是僵尸吗 - 闭嘴吧
- Are you a zombie? - Stop it.
- 我是个僵尸吗 - 别扯淡了
- Am I a zombie? - You're not even close.
你来自另一个时空吗 就像平行宇宙
Are you from another dimension? Like a parallel universe
彼此相似却又不同
where things are like this universe but different?
你是那里的蜘蛛侠
And you're Spider- Man in that universe?
然后你穿越到了这里
But somehow traveled to this universe,
但是你不知道为什么
but you don't know how?
你真的只是随便猜猜的
Wow. That was really just a guess?
其实我们在物理课上学过
We learned about it in physics.
- 量子理论 - 这太酷了
- Quantum theory. - This is amazing!
你可以像彼得说的那样教我了
You can teach me like Peter said he would.
他生前的时候给我留下了一些话
Before he died.
- 对 没错 - 好吧
- Yeah. Exactly. - Yeah, right.
听着 我答应过他的
Look, I made a promise to him.
我现在就来教你第一课 小子
Here's lesson number one, kid.
别光着听 要仔细看
Don't watch the mouth. Watch the hands.
彼得 我是认真的
Peter, seriously...
相信我 孩子
Trust me, kid.
这样你会过得轻松点
This'll all make you a better Spider- Man.
嘿你还好吗
Hey, are you okay?
不很不好
No, I'm not.
你的身体怎么了
What's going on with your body?
我的原子可能不太适应
I don't think my atoms are real jazzed
这个错误的时空
about being in the wrong dimension.
听着 我不是来应聘兼职
Look, I'm not looking for a side gig
当蜘蛛侠教练的
as a Spider- Man coach.
在我的世界我还有很多事情要处理
I got a lot going on in my dimension.
力量越大 责任越
"With great power comes great..."
别在我面前说那句话
Don't you dare finish that sentence.
别再说了 我受够了
Don't do it! I'm sick of it.
想要我的意见 做回一个普通小孩吧
Want my advice? Go back to being a regular kid.
我根本没得选
I don't have a choice!
金并造了一架对撞机
Kingpin's got a supercollider.
他想要杀了我
He's tryin' to kill me.
- 你刚才说什么 - 金并要杀了我
- What did you just say? - Kingpin's tryin' to kill me.
谁关心这个 对撞机在哪里
Who cares about that. Where's the collider?
布鲁克林 菲斯克大楼下
Brooklyn. Under Fisk Tower.
- 再见 - 你要去哪里
- Goodbye. - Where you going?
等它再启动时 只要跳进去
When it runs again, I'll jump in
- 就能回家了 - 不能重启对撞机
- and get back to my life. - You can't let them run it.
我的任务就是要摧毁它
I'm supposed to destroy it
阻止它再次启动 否则所有人都会死
so it never runs again or everyone's gonna die.
否则所有人都会死 他们每次都爱说这句话
"Or everyone's gonna die." That is what they always say.
但是“所有人都会死”之前总还会有点时间
But there's always a little bit of time before everybody dies
这时就要看我的了
and that's when I do my best work.
你难道不需要这个吗
Aren't you gonna need this?
你有个小玩意 交给我
Aw, you have a goober. Give it.
等等 不 没那么容易 他管它叫重载钥匙
Wait, no. Not so fast. He called it an override key.
总会有些什么超级钥匙 破解钥匙 管他叫什么的钥匙
There's always a bypass key, a virus key, a who- cares key.
我也记不住那么多
I can never remember,
所以我索性叫他们小玩意 给我
so I always call it a goober. Give it.
我需要用它摧毁对撞机
I need it to destroy the collider.
我需要它帮我回家
I need it to go home.
不行 再逼我 我就吞了它
I'll swallow it. Don't play with me.
- 什么 - 我说
- What? - I said...
对撞机打开了入口把我带到了这里
The collider created a portal that brought me here.
所以我得
And I have to get...
- 你把它搞坏了 - 不 它本来就是坏的
- Did you break this? - No, it broke.
我不记得发生了什么
I don't remember what happened.
看到没 所以我才不要孩子 简直太明智了
See, this is why I never had kids.
我们不能再做一个吗
Can't we make another one?
不 这里没你什么事 对亏了你
We can't do anything. Thanks to you,
我要重复那个家伙的工作 去炼金术公司
I have to re- steal what your guy stole from Alchemax
再偷一次数据 做个新钥匙
and make another one of these.
如果你走之后我没能关掉对撞机
If I don't turn off the collider after you leave,
这座城市的每个人
everyone in this city,
我的父母 我的叔叔 成千上万的人都会死
my parents, my uncle and millions of others, will die.
你打算就这么一走了之
And you're just gonna go home
把我一个人留在这里面对这一切
and leave me here to figure this out for myself?
- 你做的出这种事吗 蜘蛛侠 - 做得出啊
- You good with that, Spider- Man? - Yeah.
你蹲在那里干嘛
What are you doing?
让你良心不安吗 有效果吗
Making you feel guilty. Is it working?
怎么可能 没有 你看我
How could it...? No. Look at me.
像是有效果的样子吗
Does it look like it's working?
不没有 当然没有
No. No, it's not...
不不不不能让他得逞
No! No! No! Do not let him win!
好吧 孩子 你赢了
All right, kid. You win.
走吧 我们没有时间浪费了
Come on, we don't have a second to lose.
我超喜欢这个汉堡 太好吃了
Mmm. I love this burger. So delicious.
从没吃过这么好吃的汉堡
One of the best burgers I've ever had.
在我们那儿 这个地方六年前就关门了
In my universe, this place closed six years ago.
真搞不懂 明明这么好吃
I don't know why. I really don't.
你带钱了吧 我最近手头紧
You have money, right? I'm not very liquid right now.
- 说正经事好吗 - 当然
- Can we focus? - Mm- hm. Sure.
- 另一个彼得 - 你不吃吗
- The other Peter... - You gonna eat that?
我在听呢
I'm listening.
另一个彼得之前说
The other Peter said he was gonna be
他会教我几招
- showing me the ropes. - Wow.
你有什么蜘蛛侠诀窍可以教我的吗
You got any Spider- Man tips you can tell me now?
多了去了
Yeah, I got plenty.
面具要消毒
Disinfect the mask.
穿紧身衣要扑点爽身粉
You're gonna wanna use baby powder in the suit,
尤其是关节部位
heavy on the joints.
你也不想出疹子对吧
You don't want any chafing, right?
- 还有别的吗 - 没有了 就这些
- Anything else? - Nope, that was everything.
你这老师也太差劲了吧
I think you're gonna be a bad teacher.
查查炼金术公司在哪里
Uh- uh- uh? Look up where Alchemax is.
纽约哈德逊山谷的一家私人科技园区
"A private technological campus in Hudson Valley, New York."
炼金术公司研究所 纽约哈德逊山谷
你可以教我
You can teach me
怎么荡过去 咻咻
to swing on the way there.
我们不可能一路荡到哈德逊山谷的迈尔斯
I'm not swinging to the Hudson Valley, Miles.
尤其是吃了汉堡大餐后
Not after a hearty burger breakfast.
节省点体力 你会感谢我的
Keep your legs fresh. You're gonna thank me later.
♪ I can see a new horizon ♪
♪ Underneath the blazing sky ♪
♪ I'll be where the eagle's Flying higher... ♪
- 还有别穿斗篷 - 我觉得还挺酷的
- And it's a no on the cape. - I think it's cool.
快脱掉 丢死人了
Take that off. It's disrespectful.
蜘蛛侠不穿斗篷
Spider- Man doesn't wear a cape.
我们要怎么重复彼得的工作
So how do we retrace Peter's steps?
这是个好问题
That's a good question.
如果我是我 我会怎么做
What would I do if I were me?
有了
Got it.
第一步 先潜入实验室
Step One: I infiltrate the lab.
第二步 找到首席科学家的电脑
Two: Find the head scientist's computer.
那位推自行车的女士就是
That lady with the bike is the head scientist.
我在学校的纪录片里见过她
I saw her in this documentary.
很好 第三步 暂时抛开我个人的偏见
Cool! Step Three: I reexamine my personal biases.
第四步 黑进她的电脑
Step Four: I hack the computer.
其实也不算是黑进去
It's not technically hacking.
行了 别打断我思路
Not now. I just lost my train of thought.
第五步 下载重要信息
Step Five: Download the important stuff.
我看到就知道了
I'll know it when I see it.
然后第六步 在餐厅偷个面包圈 然后就跑
Step Six: I grab a bagel from the cafeteria and run.
那我要干嘛
So, what am I doing?
第七步 你在这里把风 非常重要
Step Seven: You stay here. You're lookout. Very important.
听着伙计 你得教我蜘蛛侠的技巧
Look, man. You gotta teach me how to do Spider- Man stuff
这样我才能帮你忙
or I won't be able to help.
学着点小子 一会儿我来考你
Watch and learn, kid! I'll quiz ya later!
为什么我要跟这
Why did I get stuck with
个又老又丑的流浪汉蜘蛛侠一起
the janky, old, broke hobo Spider- Man?!
新技能
That's new.
金并
Kingpin.
我在干嘛 我在干嘛
What am I doing? What am I doing?
彼得
Peter!
- 你在这干嘛 - 金并来了
- What are you doing here? - Kingpin's here.
你往边上去点
Just move over.
拜托你压着我脚了 赶紧爬出去
You're steppin' on my foot. Go back outside.
不 我不能眼睁睁看着蜘蛛侠遇难
No! I can't sit there and let Spider- Man die
自己却什么都不做
without doing anything about it.
我不会再那么做了
I'm not doing that again.
怎么了
What?
我遇到的那些人都想杀了我 所以
Most people I meet in the workplace try to kill me,
换种画风也不错
so you're a nice change of pace.
菲斯克先生 请看数据
Mr. Fisk! Look at this data.
我知道你可能看不明白这些数字的具体含义
I know you can't really understand it,
但这些数字表示情况大好
but these are really good numbers.
我知道密码了
And I got the password.
菲克斯先生 如果本周再次重启对撞机
Mr. Fisk. If we fire again this week
布鲁克林的下面就会产生一个黑洞
there could be a black hole under Brooklyn.
您看这个 还有这个
You see this? And this?
这就是平行宇宙
This is multiple dimensions
开始互相挤压的迹象
beginning to crash into each other.
这是蜘蛛侠剧情的老套路
This is pretty standard Spider- Man stakes.
要慢慢习惯 看好了
You get used to it. Watch this.
他会说 我再给你24小时
He's gonna say, "You've got 24 hours."
我再给你24小时
You've got 24 hours.
这么做的话可能会导致
What this means is there could be a rupture
时空连续体里出现裂缝
in the space- time continuum.
这太糟了
Ooh. That's bad.
其实她说的句句都很糟糕
Actually, everything she said was bad.
之前是逗你的
I was lying before.
等会 我再给你一些数据
Hold on. Let me get you some more data.
- 你在干嘛 伙计 - 我动不了了
- What are you doing, bud? - I can't move.
好了 放松你的手指
Okay, relax your fingers.
我们没时间了 放手 放掉就好 进入状态
We don't have time. Just let go. Be in the moment.
我在状态里 而且是糟糕的状态
I am in the moment. It's a terrible moment.
- 我不是在拒绝进入状态 - 别再找借口了
- I'm not refusing. - No more excuses.
我只是需要时间
I just need more time.
他们就在外面 你会被发现的
They're right there. They're gonna see you.
迈尔斯 你得赶紧松手
Miles, you gotta unstick.
你一般怎么做才会放松
What do you do to relax?
放松 好的 好的
Relax. Okay, okay, okay.
♪ Needless to say, I... ♪
我的天哪
Oh, for crying out loud.
♪ Callin' it quits Now, baby, I'm a wreck ♪
♪ You're a wreck, ooh... ♪
小屁孩果然不靠谱
Teenagers: just the worst.
- 迈尔斯 你去哪儿了 - - 我就在这里
- Miles, where did you go? - I'm right here.
- 在哪儿 我看不到你 - 我就在你面前
- Where? I can't see ya. - I'm right in front of you.
- 蜘蛛侠能隐身吗 - 在我们那儿不行
- Can Spider- Man turn invisible? - Not in my universe.
你戳到我眼睛了
Aah! You just poked me in my eye!
真是不可思议 像是打不过就溜的技能
This is incredible. Some kind of fight or flight thing.
什么意思
What's that?
- 把密码记下来 - Dgfampesand
Remember this password. D- G- F- A- M- P- E- S- A- N- D...
慢点
Slow down!
4$3587653454535
- 4- $- 3- 5- 8- 7- 6- 5- 3- 4- 5- 4- 5- 3- 5.
- 我得写下来 - 接着下载设计图
- I need to write it down! - Download the schematic.
- 我要怎么做 - 然后看我使出美男计
- How do I do that? - While I turn on the charm.
蜘蛛侠
Spider- Man?
嘿 刚才没看到你
Oh, hey. Didn't see you there.
好吧 我有点被吓着了
Okay, I'm kinda freaking out right now.
我是说 你应该死了才对
You're supposed to be dead.
没想到吧 好吧 这样可不行 我不习惯那样
Surprise! Okay. That's a no- no. We don't like that.
真是太神奇了
This is fascinating.
好吧 这是我的脸
Okay, that's my face.
一个完全不同的彼得帕克
An entirely different Peter Parker.
好吧 有点小肚腩 可能是因为空间扭曲
Little bit of a gut, perhaps from dimensional warping.
对对对 穿越前我比现在瘦多了
Oh, yeah- yeah- yeah. I was way flatter before I warped.
在平行宇宙中穿越
Travel through the multiverse
似乎让情况恶化...
appears to have deteriorated the...
接下去是什么
What was the rest?!
嘿 你多大了
Hey, how old are you?
你看上去不超过35岁
'Cause you don't look a day over 35.
他们都说我疯了 他们说我疯了
They said I was crazy! They said I was crazy!
告诉他们你没有疯
You showed 'em you're not crazy.
可能会有点痛
This might pinch a little.
我知道 我只需要取一些样本
I know. I just need to get these samples.
好吧
Okay.
就不能整理一下桌面吗 女士
Organize your desktop, lady.
体内的细胞正在发生衰变
Wow. Just complete cellular decay.
从来没有见过这种状况
I've never seen anything like this.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我把这些全部拿走好了
I'm just taking the whole thing.
很明显 你出故障了
And obviously you've been glitching.
故障 不 你为什么这么说
"Glitchin'"? No. Why would you even say that?
你在这个空间呆太久了
If you stay in this dimension too long,
你的身体正在瓦解
your body's gonna disintegrate.
知道这会有多痛吗 彼得·帕克
Do you know how painful that would be, Peter Parker?
不知道
I don't know.
你根本想象不到
You can't imagine.
而我
And I, for one,
迫不及待想要见证那一刻
can't wait to watch.
你叫什么名字来着
What did you say your name was?
奥利维亚·奥克塔维厄斯博士
Dr. Olivia Octavius.
我猜你的朋友是不是都叫你章鱼博士
Can I assume that your friends call you Doc Ock?
我朋友都叫我丽芙
My friends actually call me Liv.
我的敌人才叫我章鱼博士
My enemies call me Doc Ock.
这儿交给我 你快走
I got this! Run!
你在跟谁说话
Who are you talking to?
- 我能搞定 - 你搞得定吗 彼得
- I got it! - Oh, you "got it," Peter?
我稳得住 伙计
I got it handled, buddy!
一切尽在掌握
Everything is fine!
好吧 现在
Okay, this is
- 不太妙了 - 你废话还真多
- a little bit bad. - You're chatty.
我们要走了
Gotta go.
可能我今天要交待在这了
This is the moment that I'm losin' the fight.
好吧 告诉你个好消息 我们不需要显示器
Let me tell you the good news. We don't need the monitor.
彼得
Peter!
你怎么没有告诉我你还有个会隐身的朋友
You didn't tell me you had an invisible friend!
把电脑给我好吗 年轻人
Could you give me that back, young man?
彼得
Peter!
这是私人财产
It's proprietary.
这种情况
This'd be a good time
- 还是隐身比较好 - 没错
- to turn invisible. - Yep.
好吧 那你怎么还不隐 挑一个面包圈
Okay, not gonna turn invisible. Selecting a bagel.
要表现的无比正常
Act super normal.
蜘蛛侠
Spider- Man?
搞笑的是
You know, that's funny,
- 很多人都会认错 - 嘿
- I get that a lot. - Hey.
- 是蜘蛛侠 - 举起手来
- Spider- Man? - Hey! Hands up!
好了 交换一下
Now we do a switchy- switchy.
给我回来
Get back here!
你们想去哪里
Where do you think you're going?
- 他偷了面包圈 - 好了 准备荡起来
- He took a bagel! - Time to swing,
- 就像我教你的那样 - 你什么时候教过我
- just like I taught ya. - When did you teach me that?
也对 我只是开个玩笑 增进感情
I didn't. It's a little joke for team- building.
- 准备好了吗 - 当然没有
- All right, you ready? - Of course I'm not ready!
我还做不到
I can't do this yet!
大家都知道 一个人在生死关头
Everybody knows that the best way to learn
可以做到许多本来做不到的事
is under intense life- threatening pressure.
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on.
你在下面做什么
What are you doing down there?
我跑的比荡得快
I run better than I swing.
你得荡起来 不然他们会抓住你的
You gotta swing or they'll catch you.
这就是你想学的
This is what you wanted.
快回来 小家伙
Come back, little boy.
以胯部为准线 瞄准目标位置
Aim with your hips! Look where you want it to hit.
肩膀放平 别忘了后续动作
Square your shoulders. Don't forget to follow through!
重心在后脚时不要发射
Don't shoot off your back foot.
- 太多了记不住 - 那就别管我说的
- That's too many things! - Then stop listening to me!
这是你今天给的最有用的建议
That's the best idea you've had all day!
漂亮 迈尔斯
Nice, Miles!
很好 你做到了
Good. You're doin' it.
轻按两下松开 然后再发射一次
Double tap to release and thwip it out again.
懂了 发射然后松开
Thwip and release.
- 发射 松开 发射 - 松开
- And thwip. Release. Thwip. - And release.
悟性不错 发射 松开
You're a natural. Thwip. Release.
- 找到节奏了吗 - 发射 松开
- Feel the rhythm? - Thwip. And release!
很不错 迈尔斯
Good, Miles.
我想说 你超酷的 伙计
I gotta say, you're amazing, man.
我们这算是组了个小团队了
We're a little team!
我是实力不减当年的老师
Me as the teacher who could still do it.
你资质不错 但和我当年比还差点
You as the student who can do it, just not as good.
真为我们骄傲 你有什么想对我说的吗
I'm proud of us. Is there something you want to say to me?
彼得
Peter!
搞什么 谁干的
- What the...? - Who did that?
嘿伙计们
Hey, guys.
格温达
Gwanda?
是格温才对
It's Gwen, actually.
你认识她 真是不错
Oh, you know her. Very cool.
我来自另一个时空
I'm from another dimension.
我是说 除了另一个 还有一个
I mean, another- another dimension.
好吧 各位 我们再从头来一次
All right, people. Let's start at the beginning one last time.
《蜘蛛格温》
我叫格温·史黛西
My name is Gwen Stacy.
我被一只受过辐射的蜘蛛咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
在接下来的两年里
And for the last two years,
我成为了唯一的女蜘蛛侠
I've been the one and only Spider- Woman.
剩下的你们都知道了
You guys know the rest.
我加入了乐队
I joined a band.
救了我爸爸
Saved my dad.
可我却没能救下我最好的朋友
I couldn't save my best friend,
彼得·帕克
Peter Parker,
所以我发誓要救其他人
so now I save everyone else.
于是我决定再也不交朋友了
And I don't do friends anymore,
避免一切干扰
just to avoid any distractions.
突然有一天 奇怪的事发生了
And one day this weird thing happened.
这次的情况真的很奇怪
And I mean, like, really weird.
我穿越到了上个星期
I was blown into last week.
一点都不夸张
Literally.
我回到了纽约 可不是我的纽约
I landed in New York, but not my New York.
幸运的是
Lucky for these folks,
蜘蛛侠出现 拯救了他们
Spider- Man was there to save the day.
我的蜘蛛直觉告诉我我得去愿景学校
My Spider- sense told me to head to Visions Academy.
只是你们来的早了
...you guys are early.
我也不知道为什么 直到遇上了你
Wasn't sure why until I met you.
我喜欢你的发型
I like your haircut.
你还好意思说
You don't get to like my haircut.
我们走
Let's go.
到底有多少蜘蛛侠
How many more Spider- People are there?
自己去动漫展上看吧
Save it for Comic- Con.
动漫展是什么
What's Comic- Con? Whoa!
受死吧 蜘蛛侠
You're dead, Spider- Man.
威尔逊 你在做什么
Wilson! What are you doing?
瓦内莎
Vanessa.
理查德 快走
Richard, come on.
瓦内莎 理查德
Vanessa! Richard!
不
No!
别往后看 亲爱的 没事的没事的
Don't look back, honey. It's okay. It's okay.
我明明杀了蜘蛛侠
I killed Spider- Man.
为什么又多出来两个
Why did I just see two more?
准确说是三个
There's three, actually.
不 这是好事 非常非常好
No, this is good. This is very, very good.
这意味着你的目的达到了
This means you get what you want.
我的对撞机起作用了
It means my collider works.
现在我们要做的就是 灭掉那几只蜘蛛
All we have to do is kill a couple of Spiders.
然后你的家人就能回到你的身边
And the collider will bring your family back.
想要多少就有多少
As many families as you want.
明天启动我的对撞机
Tomorrow, at my collider.
是我们的对撞机
Our collider.
是他弄坏的吗
He broke this?
对 他也觉得很不好意思
Yeah. He's actually really embarrassed about it,
所以就当没这事好吗
so just keep it between us, okay?
我知道哪里能做个新的
I know where we can make a new one.
这次不会再让他弄坏了
And we won't let him break it this time.
你朋友的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about your friend.
谢谢你 迈尔斯
Thanks, Miles.
我知道这有多艰难
I know how hard this is.
要一个人面对这一切
To have to figure this stuff out on your own.
知道自己不是一个人感觉还不错
It's kinda nice not being the only Spider- person around.
是啊
Yeah.
如果哪天你愿意交朋友了
If you ever decide to do friends again,
我可以给你留个位置
I could always open up a slot.
到时候我会告诉你的
I'll keep you posted.
好的
Cool.
不如我们还是走吧
We should probably go.
彼得 都已经到门口了
Peter, we're literally on the doorstep.
太糟了 太糟了 这主意太糟了
Bad idea. This is a bad idea.
放轻松
Just relax.
谢谢你们的关心
You guys are all very sweet,
但今天不接待粉丝了 谢谢
but no more fans today, please.
我还没做好心理准备
I'm not ready for this.
彼得
Peter?
嘿 梅婶婶
Hey, Aunt May.
我知道这听起来有些疯狂
So this is gonna sound crazy,
不过 我其实是来自
but I'm pretty sure that I'm from an...
另一个时空
An alternate dimension.
没错
Yeah.
你看起来很累 彼得
You look tired, Peter.
好吧 我确实很累
Well, I am tired.
- 有点苍老 而且还丰满了 - 对 已经有人说过了
- And older. And thicker. - Yeah. I've heard that already.
天哪 这是条宽松裤吗
Oh, jeez. Are those sweatpants?
没错 就是宽松裤
Yup, that's what they are.
彼得走的时候
I was there,
我就在现场
when it all happened.
我真的很抱歉
I am so sorry.
你又是从哪个空间来的
And what dimension are you from?
布鲁克林
Brooklyn.
彼得有没有什么地方让我们重新做一个这个
Did Peter have a place where we could make another one of these?
是小玩意
A goober.
跟我来
Follow me.
好吧 我也有这么个地方
Oh, yeah, I got one of these, too.
存放装备的小屋子
A little, old shed where I keep my Spider- gear.
这地方也太能作了
I mean, this place is pretentious.
伙计 你那儿也和这里一样
Dude. Was yours anything like this?
差不多吧
Mine was like this,
不过没有吉普和飞机
but take away the jeep, the plane.
想象一下是这里的缩小版 再多加一张床垫
Imagine it way smaller. Imagine a futon.
我真为这家伙感到难过
I feel sad for this guy.
嘿 彼得
Hey, Peter.
这不是斗篷吗
I think this is a cape.
彼得知道他的使命有多危险
Peter knew how dangerous the job was.
可他知道这世上唯一能阻止那家伙的
But he figured the only one who could stop this guy
只有蜘蛛侠
was Spider- Man.
金并知道我们会去找他
Kingpin knows we're coming.
可惜我们寡不敌众
We're going to be outnumbered.
那可不一定
Don't be so sure.
你们可能会用到这个
You might need these.
你们以为只有你们想到要来这儿吗
You think you're the only people who thought to come here?
嘿伙计们
Hey, fellas.
他是黑白的吗
Is he in black and white?
哪里来的风 这里可是地下室
Where's that wind coming from? We're in a basement.
不管到哪儿 冷风总是相随
Wherever I go, the wind follows.
而这风 终将幻化成雨
And the wind, it smells like rain.
大家好
Hi, guys!
敢不敢再诡异一点
This could literally not get any weirder.
还有更诡异的
It can get weirder.
我刚洗了手 所以他才是湿的
I just washed my hands. That's why they're wet.
没别的原因
No other reason.
你们和我一样
You're like me.
《超凡蜘蛛侠》 《蜘蛛格温》 《蜘猪侠》 《潘妮·帕克》 《暗影蜘蛛侠》
暗影蜘蛛侠
我叫做彼得帕克
My name is Peter Parker.
我叫做潘妮帕克
My name is Peni Parker.
潘妮·帕克
我叫做彼得波克
My name is Peter Porker.
彼得·波克
我被一只受过辐射的蜘蛛咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
我被一只受过辐射的猪咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive pig.
在我的宇宙 现在是1933年
In my universe, it's 1933,
我是名私家侦探
and I'm a private eye.
我爱喝 蛋蜜乳
I like to drink egg creams,
也喜欢打击纳粹 非常喜欢
and I like to fight Nazis. A lot.
我来自3145年的纽约
I'm from New York in the year 3145.
我爸的机器人里面住着一只蜘蛛
I have a psychic link with a spider
我和他有心灵感应
who lives inside my father's robot.
我们是一辈子的好朋友
And we're best friends. Forever.
有时候我会让火柴一直燃烧到指尖
Sometimes I let matches burn down to my fingertips
只是为了能有点感觉
just to feel something, anything.
我是《嗥叫日报》
I'm a photographer
的摄影师
for the Daily Beagle.
工作时间
When I'm not pooching around,
我会像狗狗一样
I'm working like a dog,
到处挖劲爆新闻
trying to sniff out the latest story.
♪ I frolic and I dance ♪
♪ And I do this With my pants ♪
好了 可以了
Okay! Enough!
那么你们是怎么来的
So how did you get here?
好吧 这可就说来话长了
Well, it's kind of a long story.
或许也没那么长
Maybe not that long.
现在 我们只想回家
And now we're just trying to find a way home.
回家的唯一方法就是跳进那个对撞机
The only way home is back through that collider gizmo.
唯一的问题就是
The only trouble is...
得有个人留下来毁了那机器
One of us has to stay behind and destroy it.
- 我留下来 - 我留下来 - 我留下来
- I'll do it. - I'll do it. - I'll do it.
不不不 你们不明白
No, no, no. You guys don't get it.
不明白什么
Don't get what?
你们不能留在这儿 留在这 你们会死的
None of you can stay here. If you stay here, you'll die.
应该由我来关掉那台机器
I'm the guy who's gonna turn it off.
我会等你们都回去以后再动手
And I'm gonna get you all home before I do.
我答应过他的 所以我必须做到
Look, I made a promise. So I have to keep it.
你是哪位
Who are you again?
他是迈尔斯
This is Miles.
他将会拯救平行宇宙
And he's gonna save the multiverse.
对 没错
Yeah, man.
这小子会隐身术
This kid can turn himself invisible.
看好了 他现在就能隐形
Watch this. He can do it now.
- 我不能说隐身就隐身 - 他不能说隐身就隐身
- I can't do it on command. - He can't do it on command.
但还是很酷 给他们展示一下电击 迈尔斯
But it is cool. Show 'em the zappy thing, Miles.
- 我不能说来就来 - 他不能说来就来
- Can't do it on command. - He can't do it on command.
但他还有其他技能 比如什么来着
But he can do so much more. What else do you do?
- 只有这两样 - 只有这两样
- Just those two things. - Just those two things.
好吧
Aw, man.
听着我见过他其他技能 他很有潜力
Look, I've seen him in action. He's got potential.
我想他能送我们回家
I think he's gonna get us home.
好吧 年轻人
Okay, little fella,
金并会派很多坏蛋去找你
Kingpin's gonna send a lot of mugs after ya.
个个都很难缠 真正的大块头
I'm talkin' hard boys, real biscuit boxers.
你能一次性搞定他们吗
Can you fight them all off at once?
其实我还没跟别人交过手
I haven't actually fought anyone.
出其不意
Surprise attack!
你能在交火时重新组装主机吗
Can you rewire a mainframe while being shot at?
- 你说什么 - 让我看看
- Can I what? - Show me!
出其不意
Surprise attack!
你能像舞蹈家那样优雅地在半空中回荡吗
Can you swing and flip with the grace of a trained dancer?
你能控制住自己的情绪
Can you close off your feelings so you don't get crippled
不为自己的暴行而感到内疚吗
by the moral ambiguity of your violent actions?
你能帮你婶婶在相亲网站上注册账号
Can you help your aunt create an online dating profile
让她偶尔出去约个会吗
so she can get out of the dang house once in a while?
你闻到美食时 能飘飘欲仙吗
Can you float through the air when you smell a delicious pie?
- 你够坚强吗 - 够无情吗
- Can you be strong? - Ruthless?
- 够自律吗 - 我不知道 或许吧
- Disciplined? - I don't know. Maybe.
- 能心灵感应吗 - 展现你的勇气 士兵
- Psychic? - Show me some moxie, soldier!
最重要的是 不管你被打趴下几次
Above all, no matter how many times you get hit,
你都能站起来吗
can you get back up?
做蜘蛛侠最重要的是
'Cause when a Spider- Man is on the floor...
当你坚持不下去时
When you think you can't keep goin'...
- 起来 迈尔斯 - 起来 迈尔斯 你能做到的
- Come on, Miles. - Come on. You can do it.
- 你能做到的 - 伙计们 行了
- You can do this. - Guys, cool it.
- 你做得到的 - 起来 迈尔斯
- Come on. You can do it! - Get up, Miles.
迈尔斯 站起来
Come on, Miles. Get up.
你不能自欺欺人
You need to be more honest with yourself about this.
他还没有准备好 这很明显
He's not ready. It's obvious.
行不通的 他只是个孩子
There's no way. He's just a kid.
如果他不行
If he can't do this,
我们中就得留下一人 替他完成任务
we have to stay and do it for him.
他在那儿 听得到我们在说他
He's looking right at us while we talk about him.
迈尔斯
Miles?
看到没
You see that? He can, um...
他真的会隐身
He can turn invisible.
♪ When it gets dark Outside ♪
♪ In you I confide ♪
语音信箱:来自爸爸的未读消息
♪ You help me face my demons I won't hide... ♪
迈尔斯 你怎么回事
Miles, what is going on with you?
大家都没有你的消息 我们不知道你是怎么回事
Nobody's heard from you. We don't know what's going on.
如果你有事瞒着我们 赶紧坦白
If you're hidin' something from us, you need to come clean.
马上打给我
You call me back. Now.
医院
他也不接我的电话
He's not answering me either.
亚伦·戴维斯 拨号中
我是艾伦 我要出城几天
It's Aaron. I'm outta town for a few days.
回来再打给你 再见
I'll hit you when I'm back. Peace.
艾伦 是我杰夫
Aaron, it's Jeff.
如果你有迈尔斯的消息 马上打给我
Look, I need you to call me if you've heard from Miles.
他对你
He has a...
他对你总是那么信任
He has a soft spot for you,
我们和他失去联系了
and we haven't heard from him.
如果不是情况紧急 我是不会找你的
And you know I wouldn't reach out if this wasn't important.
希望一切都好
Hope you're good.
亲爱的艾伦叔叔
Dear Uncle Aaron.
我得去完成一件事 但我不知道能不能行
I gotta do something, and I don't know if I can do it.
我很害怕 叔叔
I'm scared, man.
我受够了让所有人都失望
I'm just tired of lettin' everybody down.
你是我唯一能够倾诉的人
You're the only one I can talk to.
真希望你能在这儿
I just wish you were here.
你好 菲斯克先生
Hello, Mr. Fisk.
我从隧道那儿拿到了监控录像
I've got the security tapes from the tunnel right here.
只要他还在这 我会找到他的
If the kid's out there, I'll find him.
你了解我的先生 我从不放弃
You know me, sir. I don't ever quit.
探测到热量
♪ Personal insanity They gotta like the ally ♪
♪ Turn it up Against the rally ♪
♪ You're running in While they're counting ♪
♪ Even score, got the tally Knock 'em off at the finale ♪
♪ Go, go! They don't want it, yeah ♪
♪ They don't want it, yeah ♪
这个是
This is...
- 紫色 - 不
- Purple. - No.
- 蓝色 - 不
- Blue? - No.
有迈尔斯的消息吗
Has anyone heard from Miles?
他只是需要冷静一下 我了解那孩子
Look, he's just clearing his head. I know the kid.
他能搞得定
He's got what it takes.
我敢打赌他一定会跨过那扇门
I bet you he's gonna come back through that door,
振作起来 准备好迎战
recharged and ready to fight.
- 我叔叔 - 嘿 你去哪儿了
- My uncle. - Hey, where have you been?
我的叔叔艾伦 他是徘徊者
My uncle Aaron, he's the Prowler.
- 慢慢说 迈尔斯 - 他是金并的手下
- Slow down, Miles. - He works for Kingpin.
他想要杀了我
He tried to kill me!
这剧情也太简单粗暴了吧
This is a pretty hard- core origin story.
没事的 我们会调查清楚的
It's okay. We're gonna figure it out.
- 有人跟踪你吗 - 不 我想 应该没有
- Were you followed? - No, I don't think so.
- 地方不错 真是温馨 - 好极了 是丽芙
- Cute place. Real homey. - Oh, great. It's Liv.
我想我被跟踪了
I guess I was followed.
哦 不
Oh, no.
快走迈尔斯
Get out of here, kid.
你可闯大祸了 小子 太粗心了
You messed up bigtime, kid. Very sloppy.
让我猜猜 你是蝎子 我们是蜘蛛 算是远亲
Let me guess. You're Scorpion. Well, we're the Spider gang.
你们介不介意到外面解决
Would you mind taking this outside?
我们跳起舞来从不挑场子
We don't pick the ballroom, we just dance.
那个就交给我吧
Ooh, I think I'll be taking that.
小家伙 来吧 准备受死吧
Stand, niñito, dale. Prepárate a morir.
天 愚蠢的垫子
Man, stupid pillows.
都说让你们出去解决了
I said, take it outside!
我来 我来
I got it!
- 交给我伙计 - 别碰那个孩子
I got this, buddy. Leave the kid alone!
不不不
No, no, no! No!
快离开 伙计
You gotta go, man.
所有车辆请注意 发生骚乱事件
All vehicles in the area, we have a disturbance
嫌疑人为蜘蛛侠们
involving multiple Spiderpeople?
收到 这就去
Yeah. On my way.
把它交给我
Give me that thing.
别傻了 小子 快交给我
Don't be stupid, kid. Hand it over, now!
你无路可逃了
Nowhere left to run.
迈尔斯
Miles?
艾伦叔叔
Uncle Aaron.
不不不不
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
求你了 艾伦叔叔
Please, Uncle Aaron.
徘徊者
Prowler.
你还在等什么 解决掉他
What are you waitin' for? Finish it.
快离开这儿
Get out of here!
不
No.
迈尔斯
Miles.
艾伦叔叔
Uncle Aaron.
这都是我的错
This is my fault.
不 迈尔斯
No, Miles.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
是我骗了你 我想让你崇拜我
I wanted you to look up to me.
是我让你失望了
I let you down, man. I let you down.
你是我们中最棒的 迈尔斯
You're the best of all of us, Miles.
你有属于自己的路
You're on your way.
你要坚持下去
Just keep going.
坚持下去
举起手
Hands up!
把手举起来 快
Put your arms up. Now!
转过来
Turn around.
嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey!
艾伦 不 不
Aaron. Aaron, no. No!
各单位注意
All units.
请发出全境通告 通缉一位新蜘蛛侠
I want an APB on a new Spider- Man.
远大前程
嘿伙计
Hey, bud.
你没事吧
You okay?
我们都经历过
We've all been there. You know, for me,
我失去的是我的本叔叔
it was my Uncle Ben.
我失去的是我的班杰明叔叔
For me, it was my Uncle Benjamin.
我失去的是我爸爸
For me, it was my father.
我失去的是我最好的朋友
For me, it was my best friend.
迈尔斯 对我们而言最难接受的就是
Miles, the hardest thing about this job is
你不可能每次都救得了所有人
you can't always save everybody.
这都是我的错 你们不会理解的
Look, it was my fault. You wouldn't understand.
迈尔斯 我们或许是这个世界上唯一能理解你的人们了
Miles, we're probably the only ones who do understand.
糟糕
Oh, no.
♪ Who in here trying To start a riot? ♪
往那儿 往那儿
That way, that way.
另一边 另一边 另一边
Other way, other way, other way, other way.
♪ Who that swinging In the air? ♪
嘿 伙计
Hey there.
你们这儿动物会说话吗
Do animals talk in this dimension?
我可不想吓着他
'Cause I don't wanna freak him out.
♪ Let's stand up, stand up You better just fix your... ♪
你们怎么了
What's going on?
再见迈尔斯
Bye, Miles.
迈尔斯 我是来道别的
Miles, I came to say goodbye.
可以在对撞机那儿道别
We can say goodbye at the collider.
你没明白 你得留在这儿
You're not getting it. You're staying here.
我必须去 这样你们才都能回家
I need to be there. So you can all go home.
他们是要回家了 迈尔斯 我会一个人留在这里
They are going home, Miles. I'm the only one stayin'.
你要代替我完成任务么 留下的话你会死的
You're taking my place? If you stay here, you'll die.
我必须完成我该做的事
I'm doing what needs to be done.
我希望自己能亲口告诉你
I just wanted you to hear it from me.
那玛丽·简呢
What about MJ?
不是所有的事都有结果的
Not everything works out, kid.
我需要小玩意
I need the goober.
请不要逼我从你那儿抢过来
Please don't make me take it from you.
这不公平
That's not fair!
你去告诉他们我能做到
You gotta tell them I can do this.
这不是他们的决定
It wasn't their decision.
我要让金并付出代价 你必须让我回去报仇
I gotta make Kingpin pay! You have to let me make him pay!
你这样等于是去送死
Miles, you're gonna get yourself killed.
可我准备好了 我保证
But I'm ready. I promise!
那你现在就来电我
Then venom- strike me right now.
或者隐藏自己 说隐身就隐身 然后从我身边走过
Or turn invisible on command so you can get past me.
听着 我知道你很想报仇 孩子
Look, I know how much you want this, kid.
可怜的小家伙
Poor little guy.
可你还没准备好
But you don't have it yet.
对不起
I'm sorry.
彼得 怎么才知道自己准备好了
When will I know I'm ready?
你不会知道 这是一种信念
You won't. It's a leap of faith.
就这么简单 迈尔斯
That's all it is, Miles.
一种信念
A leap of faith.
迈尔斯
Miles.
迈尔斯 是爸爸
Miles, it's your dad.
把门打开好吗
Please open the door.
迈尔斯 我看得到你的影子
Miles, I can see your shadow movin' around.
好吧 也对 我能理解 你还在生我的气
Yeah, okay, I get it. I get it. You're still ignoring me.
我们能聊几句吗
Look, can we talk for a minute?
有件事
Something...
有件事发生在你...
Something happened to...
有时候人与人之间会变得疏远
Look, sometimes people drift apart, Miles.
我不希望这发生在我们身上 好吗
And I don't want that to happen to us, okay?
我知道我一直没能按照你希望的方式
I know I don't always do what you need me to do
和你相处
or say what you need me to say.
我看得到你身上的闪光点 这很了不起 所以我才会逼你
I see this spark in you. It's amazing. It's why I push you.
可这是你的人生
But it's yours.
不管你怎么选择 你都是最棒的
Whatever you choose to do with it, you'll be great.
回头记得打给我 好吗
Look, call me when you can. Okay?
我爱你
I love you.
这次你不用也说我爱你
You don't have to say it back, though.
♪ 200 miles per hour With a blindfold on ♪
♪ Mama always asking "Where did I go wrong?" ♪
这么晚才到
Took you long enough.
♪ Ah, what's up, danger? ♪
我看得到你身上的闪光点
I see this spark in you.
这很了不起
It's amazing.
不管你怎么选择 你都是最棒的
Whatever you choose to do with it, you'll be great.
我们家的人从来不逃避问题
Our family doesn't run from things.
你是我们中最棒的 迈尔斯 你有自己的路
You're the best of all of us, Miles. You're on your way.
坚持下去
Just keep going.
怎么才知道自己准备好了
When do I know I'm Spider- Man?
你不会知道
You won't.
就这么简单 迈尔斯
That's all it is, Miles.
一种信念
A leap of faith.
♪ Like, what's up, danger? ♪
我自己做的
Made 'em myself.
戴起来非常合身
They fit perfectly.
- ♪ Can't stop me now ♪ - ♪ Traveled 200 miles ♪
♪ I'm knockin' at your door And I don't really care ♪
- ♪ If you ain't done wrong ♪ - ♪ I said I got you now ♪
♪ Come on, what's up, danger? ♪
♪ Don't be a stranger ♪
♪ I'm right here at your door ♪
♪ I won't leave, I want more ♪
♪ What's up, danger? ♪
♪ Yeah, what's up, danger? ♪
♪ Can't stop me now ♪
♪ 'Cause I like high G's Sister, I might lose ♪
♪ I like it all on the edge Just like you, hey ♪
♪ I like tall buildings So I can leap off of 'em ♪
♪ I go hard with it No matter how dark it is ♪
♪ Come on, what's up, danger? ♪
《蜘蛛侠迈尔斯·莫拉莱斯》
金并有部私人电梯
Kingpin has a private elevator entrance
可以从顶楼直接通往对撞机那儿
from his penthouse to the collider below.
没想到还会有观众
Didn't count on having an audience.
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
谢谢 很荣幸今晚能和大家
Thank you. It's nice to be with you this evening
一起纪念蜘蛛侠
to celebrate Spider- Man.
我们曾是很好的朋友 他就像
He and I were very close.
- 真是个猪头 - 我听得到你说的话
- What a pig. - I'm right here.
等等 看看那些服务员的打扮
Hold on. Get a load of how the waiters are dressed.
真没品味 不过
It's in poor taste, but...
不会这么容易吧
It can't be that easy.
就是这么容易
It's that easy.
很感谢今晚玛丽·简·帕克
I just wanna thank Mary Jane Parker
出席我们的晚会
for being here this evening.
玛丽·简
MJ?
集中精神 那不是你的玛丽·简 好吗
Pay attention. It's not your MJ, Peter, okay?
抱歉我马上回来
I'm sorry, I'll be right back.
彼得 别过去 相信我
Peter! Come here. Trust me.
我也经历过 你要向前看
I've been there. You gotta move on, buddy.
就一下下 我是想和她
It will take one second. Let me just... Oh!
你好
- Hello. - Oh, wow.
能不能麻烦
Um... I just wondered
给12号桌加点面包
if we could have some more bread at table 12.
好的
Yeah.
我想说 我真的很抱歉
I'm just... I'm really sorry.
不用抱歉 只是面包而已
Oh! Don't be sorry. It's just bread.
你需要我的时候 我没能出现
I wasn't there for you when you needed me.
我甚至都没尽力
- Mm- hmm. - I didn't even try.
没关系 我想我该走了
That's fine. You know, I should really get going.
我知道我能做的更好
I know I could do better
如果我还有机会
if I just had another chance
我一定会给你 你值得拥有的那些面包
to give you the bread that you deserve.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
女士 面包一会儿就送到
We'll take care of that bread right now.
很高兴能够和你聊天
Well, it's been nice talking to you.
为了你 他们应该在这里铺满新鲜的面包
For you, they should fill this place up with fresh bread.
- 你还好吧 伙计 - 是的 我很好
- You all right, man? - Oh, yeah. Totally.
那就好 我们可没空管面包的事
Good, 'cause we are not getting any bread.
我只为家人
I'm just sorry my family can't see
无法看到今晚的情况感到遗憾
what we're doing here tonight.
初始化初级点火序列
Initializing primary ignition sequence.
睡吧
Sleep.
启动程序
Start the sequence.
上传瓦内萨·菲克斯和理查德·菲克斯的基因序列
Uploading Vanessa Fisk and Richard Fisk DNA sequence.
开始搜索空间匹配
Beginning scan for dimensional matches.
二级点火倒计时开始
Secondary ignition in five, four,
三 二 一
three, two, one.
彼得你不必留下来 我能搞定
Peter, you don't have to stay behind. I can do it.
没关系
It's okay.
我已经决定了
I've made up my mind.
我会把小玩意插进去 控制光波
I'll put the goober in and take over the beam.
等你们都走了 我就炸了它
After you're gone, I'll blow it up.
祝你们好运
Good luck, guys.
他们知道我们来了
They know we're here.
很高兴再次见面 彼得
Nice to see you again, Peter.
我来掩护你
I got you covered!
这些家伙真碍事
These guys are the pits.
为什么总是这么难
Why is this always difficult?
你要去哪儿 彼得
Where you going, Peter?
有什么遗言吗
Any last words?
能给我一分钟思考一下吗 带笔了吗
Can I get a minute to think about it? You have a pen?
再见了 彼得·帕克
Goodbye, Peter Parker.
谁在那儿
Who did that?!
- 迈尔斯 - 蜘蛛侠
- Miles? - Spider- Man?
迈尔斯 你学会控制自己了
Wow, Miles. You're doing it on command!
也是时候了 对吧
It's about time, right?
- 看看谁来了 - 你做到了
- Look who's here! - You figured it out.
我爱你 真为你感到骄傲
I love you! I am so proud of you!
我想要孩子了
Do I want kids?
好吧 我差点忘了
Oh, yeah, I forgot about her.
情况看起来可不妙
Well, that doesn't look promising.
对 确实不妙
No, it doesn't.
找到基因匹配了 等等
I've got genetic matches. Hold on.
风险太大了
It's too risky.
闭上嘴 快打开
Shut up and turn it up.
- 在你左边 - 在你右边
- On your left! - On your right!
五点钟方向 三点钟 两点钟
I got five o'clock! Three o'clock! Two o'clock!
所有方向
Every direction!
快去避难所 我马上过去
Get to a shelter. I'll be right there.
我打给学校 可怎么都打不通
I tried the school, but I can't get through.
伙计们你们看到了吗
Guys, are you seeing this?
看起来像是我们的宇宙正在涌向我们
Looks like our dimensions are coming to us.
看起来还挺酷 不是吗
Does look cool though, right?
我们得回到上面去
We gotta get back up there.
你就这么点本事吗
Is that all you got?
看来你只会嘴上说说
You gonna fight or you just bumping gums?
你这个欠揍的臭乌龟
You hard- boiled turtle slapper!
一只猪 什么玩意儿 愚蠢的卡通人物吗
What are you, some kind of silly cartoon?
你对卡通人物有意见吗
You got a problem with cartoons?
我敲
Blammo!
现在觉得卡通人物怎么样
Did that feel like a cartoon?
格温
Gwen!
战服不错
I like your suit.
谢谢 我自己做的
Thanks. I made it myself.
真可爱 伙计们 现在抓紧了
That was adorable, team! Now, hold on tight!
准备好 伙计们 这将会是场苦战
Buckle up, guys. This is gonna take a while.
好吧 当我没说
All right. Never mind.
去做个了结吧
Let's end this thing.
伙计们 交给我吧
Guys, I got it.
开始了 小玩意儿还在我这儿
I'll go. I'm the one with the goo...
居然上了那小子的套
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
别光顾着听 要仔细看
Don't watch the mouth. Watch the hands.
- 迈尔斯 - 小心
- Miles! - Be careful!
还挺刺激的
That was crazy.
这都是我们教他的对吧
We taught him that, right?
我可没教过他 更不可能是你教的
I didn't teach him that. And you definitely didn't.
没事吧
You okay?
走吧
Come on.
嘿 伙计们 我控制住光束了 快上来
Guys, I got control of the beam! Get up here!
报警 量子极性正在反转
Alert! Quantum polarity has been reversed.
看来是时候了
Guess this is it.
好吧 能找到同伴真好
Well, nice to know we're not alone.
对吧
- Right? - Yeah.
我打开了入口
I got the portal open. You first, Peni.
你先走 潘妮 谢谢你迈尔斯
Thank you, Miles.
我们俩都是
From both of us.
我想说 我爱你们大家
I, uh, love you all.
我会把这小方块带回去
I'm taking this cube thing with me.
虽然还不太会玩
I don't understand it.
但我会搞懂的
But I will.
这个送给你
I want you to have this.
可以放在口袋里
It'll fit in your pocket.
朋友们 就到这儿吧
That's all, folks.
他可以这么说吗 不会侵权吗
Is he allowed to say that, legally?
现在能说我喜欢你的发型了吗
Do I get to like the hairdo now?
你知道我比你大吧
You know I'm older than you.
虽然只有15个月 但我还挺介意这点的
15 months, but it's pretty significant if you ask me.
好吧 爱因斯坦说过 时间是相对的 对吧
Well, Einstein said time was relative, right?
聪明
Nice.
我们是朋友吧
Friends?
是朋友
Friends.
好
Cool.
回头见 蜘蛛侠
See you around, Spider- Man.
该你了
Your turn.
对 对
Yeah, yeah. Right.
你哪儿都别想去
You're not going anywhere!
我去拖住他 你去把机器关掉
I'll hold him off. You shut this down.
彼得 计划不是这样的
Peter, that wasn't the deal!
按绿色的按钮 千万不要等我
Push the green button! Do not wait for me!
- 你在做什么 - 你必须得回家
- What are you doing? - You gotta go home!
这家伙会杀了你的 我不能看着蜘蛛侠死
This guy could kill you! I can't let Spider- Man die.
我也不能
Neither can I.
不会有事的
It's okay.
对 我不会让你有事的
Yeah, it is okay.
你得回去 伙计
You gotta go home, man.
我怎么知道这次会不会再被我搞砸
How do I know I'm not gonna mess it up again?
你不会知道
You won't.
对
Right.
这是种信念
It's a leap of faith.
真不赖 小子
Not bad, kid.
金并
Kingpin!
不
Nope!
那是作弊
Sorry! That's cheating.
再见了
Adiós.
哦 我得到按钮那儿去
I gotta get to that button.
不
Oh, no.
孤军奋战没想象中那么容易对吧
Not so easy doing it on your own, is it?
我迫不及待想再杀一个蜘蛛侠
I can't wait to kill one more Spider- Man.
- 我在哪 - 什么
- Where am I? - What?
威尔森
Wilson?
- 这不是你想要的吗 - 你在做什么
- Is this what you want, man? - What are you doing?
瓦内莎 瓦内莎
Vanessa. Vanessa.
- 我们在这里什么 - 我也不知道
- What are we doing here? - I don't know, Richard.
是我 你知道的
It's me. You know me.
快离开这儿
We're leaving now.
别走
Don't go.
留下来
Stay with me.
Please!
我不会让你阻止我的 这次绝对不行
You're not stopping this. Not today.
我现在就要阻止你
I am stopping this. Right now!
我需要增援
I need backup.
加把劲
Come on.
真正的蜘蛛侠都打败不了我
The real Spider- Man couldn't even beat me.
你算什么
You're nothing!
你让我失去了我的家人
You took my family.
现在 我要让你也见不到你的家人
And now I'm gonna make sure you never see yours again.
站起来 蜘蛛侠
Get up, Spider- Man.
加油 站起来
Get up! Come on!
加把劲 加把劲 加把劲
Come on. Come on. Come on.
我不会离开我的家人
I'll always have my family.
你听过搭肩膀这招吗
You ever hear of the shoulder touch?
什么
What?
嘿
Hey.
金并 帮我按下绿色按钮
Hey, Kingpin! Push the green button for me!
迈尔斯
迈尔斯 迈尔斯 你没事吧
Miles? Miles? Are you okay?
没事 我没事
Yeah, I'm okay.
你现在应该很忙 所以
You're probably busy...
不不不我有空 我有空
No! I can talk, I can talk.
我之前去找你是因为
Look, so I came by earlier because...
- 你叔叔他 - 我知道爸爸
- Your uncle... - I know, Dad.
我很难过
I am so sorry.
嗯
Yeah.
你知道是谁干的吗
Do you know who did it?
我以为我知道
I thought I did.
但是我错了
But I was wrong.
听着迈尔斯 我在你们门口说的那些话
Look, Miles, what I said at the door,
不只是说说而已
it wasn't just talk.
听着 我在想 我们可以
Look, you know, I was thinking
找一堵不错的墙
maybe we could find a nice wall,
私家的 比如警察局那堵
privately owned, like at the police station,
这样你就可以把你的作品丢到墙上去了
and you could "throw up" some of your art.
我真是不擅长说这些
Man, I'm bad at this.
迈尔斯 迈尔斯 听得到我么
Okay, Miles. Miles? You there?
这什么信号太差了
Oh, come on, man. C- Mobile!
- 警官 - 蜘蛛侠
- Officer. - Spider- Man!
听我说 刚刚在下面
Listen, down there, that was...
我真的欠你一份人情
I mean, I owe you...
好吧
Okay!
很期待以后和你并肩作战
I look forward to workin' with you.
对 我想我也是
Yeah, me, too. I guess.
虽然我不赞同你的做法
I don't approve of your methods,
但是不同的想法能擦出火花
but we're just gonna have to agree to disagree.
谢谢你今晚的伟大贡献
Thank you for your bravery tonight.
我爱你
I love you.
什么
Wait, what?
看你背后
And look behind you!
您友好的邻居蜘蛛侠献上
没错 是很酷 是的
All right. Cool. Yeah.
谢谢 蜘蛛侠
Thanks, Spider- Man.
我是蜘蛛侠 能帮到大家很高兴 谢谢你
Spider- Man, a su servicio. Thank you.
谢谢你 伙计你好吗
Hey, man. What's up, little man?
一位新蜘蛛侠
New Spider- Man.
对的 我是新的蜘蛛侠
Yeah. Yeah, I'm the new Spider- Man.
看好了
Check it out.
这个是计划内的
That was part of the move.
好吧各位我们最后再来一次
Okay, let's do this one last time, yeah?
真的是最后一次了
For real this time. This is it.
我的名字叫迈尔斯·莫拉莱斯
My name is Miles Morales.
我被一只受过辐射的蜘蛛咬了
I was bitten by a radioactive spider.
在过去两天
And for like two days,
我成为了独一无二的蜘蛛侠
I've been the one and only Spider- Man.
剩下的相信你们都知道了
I think you know the rest.
我写完了我的论文
I finished my essay.
《远大前程》 迈尔斯·莫拉莱斯作
救了很多人
Saved a bunch of people.
被无人机撞到了头
Got hit by a drone.
跟我爸一起完成了这个
I did this with my dad.
艾伦叔叔 力量不息
终于跟我的室友成为了朋友
Met my roommate. Finally.
大家好 我的名字叫蜘蛛侠
在我爸永远都找不到的地方贴了贴纸
Slapped a sticker where my dad's never gonna find it.
当我感到孤独
And when I feel alone,
没有人能够理解我的处境时
like no one understands what I'm going through,
我知道我的朋友们会懂我
I remember my friends who get it.
我从没有想过自己能做到这些
I never thought I'd be able to do any of this stuff.
可我做到了
But I can.
任何人都能戴上这个面罩
Anyone can wear the mask.
你能戴上面具
You could wear the mask.
如果你之前不了解这点 我希望你现在能了解了
If you didn't know that before, I hope you do now.
因为我是蜘蛛侠
'Cause I'm Spider- Man.
而且 我不是唯一一位蜘蛛侠
And I'm not the only one.
很长一段时间都会是如此
Not by a long shot.
♪ Needless to say I keep her in check ♪
♪ She was all bad- bad Nevertheless ♪
♪ Callin' it quits now Baby, I'm a wreck... ♪
迈尔斯 迈尔斯
Miles. Miles!
现在有空么
You got a minute?
♪ Stepped out of my zone ♪
♪ I had to get out all alone ♪
♪ And figure it out on my own ♪
♪ And I know what I really want now ♪
♪ Can't stop me Can't break me ♪
♪ What don't kill me Gon' make me ♪
♪ Shoot for the stars No safety ♪
♪ And now I see clear in HD ♪
- ♪ Gotta go hard ♪ - ♪ Gotta go hard ♪
- ♪ I ain't got time to waste ♪ - ♪ I ain't got time ♪
- ♪ I gotta go high ♪ - ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ I gotta elevate ♪ - ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
- ♪ They wanna fight ♪ - ♪ They wanna fight ♪
- ♪ I'm just gon' let 'em hate ♪ - ♪ I'm just gon' let 'em hate ♪
- ♪ I gotta go high ♪ - ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ I gotta elevate ♪ - ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
♪ You gotta choose a side You gotta choose a side ♪
♪ You better keep You better do what's right ♪
♪ Or you gonna lose the fight ♪
- ♪ You gonna ♪ - ♪ Gotta go hard ♪
♪ Gotta choose a side ♪
♪ I'm gonna elevate ♪
- ♪ You better ♪ - ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ You better do what's right ♪ - ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
♪ Heroes never die ♪
♪ I'm a web slinger To a gunslinger ♪
♪ No millimeter This is my arena ♪
♪ I'm the black widow With the best stinger ♪
♪ And I'll make you scream Like a bad singer ♪
♪ I'm everything that you Wanna be plus more ♪
♪ Since there's No heroes anymore ♪
♪ Jump out the window Him with the mask on ♪
♪ Who the bad man That our man gotta bash on? ♪
♪ Oh, we'll never link up Blink and you will see us ♪
♪ Young prince 'bout to ink up See me in the NYC ♪
♪ You can never swing by me ♪
♪ Oh, we'll never link up Blink and you will see us ♪
♪ Young prince 'bout to ink up See me in the NYC ♪
♪ Home of the B.I.G., yo ♪
♪ They just slander me I just plan to be ♪
♪ Something powerful For my family ♪
♪ Tried to balance life And my sanity ♪
♪ Show a different side Of humanity ♪
♪ So amazing, keep upraising ♪
♪ Save you from A home invasion ♪
♪ Chasing robbers From the bank ♪
♪ You facing friendly Neighborhood Spider- Man ♪
♪ Gotta go hard ♪
- ♪ I ain't got time to waste ♪ - ♪ I ain't got time ♪
- ♪ I gotta go high ♪ - ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ I gotta elevate ♪ - ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
- ♪ They wanna fight ♪ - ♪ They wanna fight ♪
- ♪ I'm just gon' let 'em hate ♪ - ♪ I'm just gon' let 'em hate ♪
- ♪ I gotta go high ♪ - ♪ Gotta go high ♪
- ♪ I gotta elevate ♪ - ♪ I gotta elevate ♪
♪ Okay, I fight crime Through the nighttime ♪
♪ When the lights shine I go python ♪
♪ I'm falling on My last lifeline ♪
♪ There's no way In my right mind ♪
♪ My city up on my back tight ♪
♪ How can I possibly Act right? ♪
♪ I'm Robin Hood I'm the black knight ♪
♪ I know you heard 'Bout my last fight ♪
♪ 'Cause I win Over and over again ♪
♪ Battling evil I'm hoping to win ♪
♪ Fighting my demons I'm nice for a reason ♪
♪ Enticed with the bleeding I'm showing my sins ♪
♪ How can you expect me To stay sane? ♪
♪ Protect me My technique go X speed ♪
♪ On highways and Jet Skis ♪
♪ Look, I ain't got no time To be hanging around nobody ♪
♪ Trying to figure out If they good or evil ♪
♪ I'm fighting the crime Saving your lives ♪
♪ One at a time I'm killing the rhymes ♪
♪ I do it for the people ♪
♪ I'm Peter Parker Running through The Six ♪
♪ With a bag full of tricks You better choose a side ♪
♪ I can promise you I will not lose this time ♪
♪ I did it all independent Now we winning ♪
♪ I got my homeys Cooking in the kitchen ♪
♪ We gon' have to win And give us the business ♪
♪ The world is mine and you Gon' have to pay me attention ♪
♪ I did everything That I did on my own ♪
♪ I'm the only one for real There can never be a clone ♪
♪ Better talk to me nice Better watch your tone ♪
♪ And I'm putting on For my home slice ♪
♪ So I gotta go hard ♪
♪ I gotta elevate ♪
蜘蛛侠:平行宇宙
- 那个理所当然且由衷而发地去帮助他人 的人毫无疑问才是一位真正的超级英雄
- 斯坦·李
- 谢谢你们 - 斯坦·李
- 史蒂夫·迪特科 - 告诉我们 我们并不是独自在战斗
♪ Yeah, yeah Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ I went from boy to a man, Why? ♪
♪ Officer sure had to Stand down ♪
♪ But I had to make A perfect plan ♪
- ♪ I'm on a wave ♪ - ♪ Brave, brave ♪
♪ I had to fight For the city ♪
♪ For the city ♪
- ♪ I had to fight for people ♪ - ♪ For the people ♪
♪ You gotta do What all leaders do, go ♪
♪ Everyone here We been needing you ♪
♪ I know you can be a hero 'Cause I seen you do it ♪
♪ This is the time We needed you ♪
♪ Everyone is here To see you move ♪
♪ We want it, we want it We want it, we want it ♪
- ♪ We put our wallet away ♪ - ♪ Wallet ♪
♪ And every time Each one of you ♪
♪ Through the city You were saving the day, go ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ We gotta fight For the town, town ♪
♪ Now there's no feelings allowed, allowed ♪
♪ Everyone cheer in the crowd ♪
♪ Bought 'em so well I'm over the clouds ♪
- ♪ We gotta fight for the city ♪ - ♪ City ♪
- ♪ Competition was lethal ♪ - ♪ Lethal ♪
- ♪ Honestly, it's no biggie ♪ - ♪ Biggie ♪
♪ I had to do What all leaders do ♪
♪ Uh- oh They don't want it, man ♪
♪ Uh- oh They don't wanna know ♪
♪ Promise, uh- oh They don't want it, man ♪
♪ Uh- oh, they can't Handle my powers ♪
♪ They always hate on us ♪
♪ But they can't do it Without us ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We gotta clean up These city streets ♪
- ♪ We don't accept defeat ♪ - ♪ 'Feat ♪
♪ We keep on going Until we win ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ All of 'em weak In the knees ♪
♪ Scary how lights When they freeze ♪
♪ Well, we keep on going Until we win ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ We are the way up ♪
♪ Well ♪
♪ This morning I woke up ♪
♪ In a fortress of distortion ♪
♪ I'm at war with my emotions ♪
♪ I'm at war with They enforce me ♪
♪ Trying to fight for what's Right, and got sidetracked ♪
♪ Where your mind at? Never mind that ♪
♪ Got me thinking a blink You swim and you sinking ♪
♪ You wouldn't, you leave me Here for my loaded weapon ♪
♪ I still owe my brother My present protection ♪
♪ My prayer, my sights So I'm doing what's right ♪
♪ And I ask you no questions ♪
♪ I wanna be home- free ♪
♪ Where's one that was lonely ♪
♪ But I'm ready and waiting ♪
♪ For my day of salvation And I'm patient ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ I'm coming home, now ♪
♪ I'm coming home ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ My rebel lone yell ♪
♪ My rebel lone ♪
♪ They looking for saviors I'm looking for safety ♪
♪ They never gonna break me Take me ♪
♪ Down on my knees, believe ♪
♪ I'm never gonna beg Or plead ♪
♪ I never say never But I guarantee ♪
♪ Gather my strength Goin' hard in the paint ♪
♪ Paint some more pictures Put on display ♪
♪ I'm a get they don't Get them my check ♪
♪ Can't take me down now ♪
♪ My feet on the ground now ♪
♪ Punchin' 'em on down now ♪
♪ Say it out loud now ♪
♪ Say it out loud Are you ready for war? ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ I'm coming home now ♪
♪ I'm coming home ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ My rebel lone yell ♪
♪ My rebel lone ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh, Spidey- bells Spidey- bells ♪
♪ Swinging through Midtown ♪
♪ Oh, what fun to sling a web ♪
♪ And take the bad guys down ♪
♪ Spidey- bells, Spidey- bells ♪
♪ Quipping all the time ♪
♪ Oh, what fun To swing around ♪
♪ New York While fighting crime ♪
♪ Swinging through The streets ♪
♪ On a web of spider silk ♪
♪ Kicking all the butts ♪
♪ Of villains and their ilk ♪
♪ Bombs from Goblins fling Fling ♪
♪ Pumpkins blooming bright Bright ♪
♪ How hard it is To consistently bring ♪
♪ Peace to New York all night ♪
♪ Oh, Spidey- bells Might be swell ♪
♪ To do more than fight crime ♪
♪ I got a lot of qualities That don't get much airtime ♪
♪ I can sing, I can dance I tell jokes, I act ♪
♪ I get big, big, big deal ♪
♪ If my agent called me back ♪
♪ Why did I agree ♪
♪ To do this stupid song? ♪
♪ I have a degree ♪
♪ In chemical engineering ♪
<font name="腾祥铚谦幼儿简\3c&H000000&\3a&HFF&\4c&H000000&\4a&HFF&\c&HFFFFFF&\pos(193.604,99.543)">与此同时 在另
一个时空的纽约
你有点来晚了
You're a bit late.
我们也不会分身术啊
We can't all be everywhere at once.
你早该给我发个短信的
Little text might've been nice.
我只不过离开了不到两小时 发生什么了
I was gone for less than two hours. What happened?
好吧 我知道看起来很糟糕
Okay. I know what it looks like.
- 但是我这也有好消息噢 - 说给我听听
- But here's the good news. - Oh, here we go.
平行宇宙并没有崩塌
The multiverse didn't collapse.
- 哇 太好啦 - 小菜一碟罢了
- Oh, cool! - Little touch and go.
麻烦解决了
But it worked out.
好一个故事 你做完你手头上那个小玩意没?
Great story. Did you finish the goober?
不是"小玩意" 是"小发明"
It's not a goober. It's a gizmo.
你非得大声叫唤我吗
Do you always have to call me out?
就是太烦太恼人了
It's just really frustrating and bums me out.
米圭尔 别太激动了
Don't get excited, Miguel.
- 这还只是原型机 - 我不激动
- It's just a prototype. - Not excited.
但你可是世界上第一位
But you could be the first person
主动穿越平行宇宙的人啊
to make an autonomous multiverse jump.
也可能是最后一位
Or the last.
所以我们就孤注一掷 听天由命咯
So we're just gonna roll the dice on this?
所以 老哥 你怎么说 先去哪
So, what you do you say, pal? Where you want to go first?
最后一次 让我们来从头了解一下
Let's start at the beginning one last time.
- 1967年蜘蛛侠动画版的宇宙
- 地球- 67 Earth '67.
<font name="腾祥铚谦幼儿简\3c&H000000&\3a&HFF&\4c&H000000&\4a&HFF&\c&H050001&\i1\pos(264.2,76.348)">地球- 67
- 哇哦 - 什么鬼玩...?
- Whoa! - What the...?
我是蜘蛛侠
I'm Spider- Man.
- 我要你和我走一趟 - 你特么是谁啊
- I need you to come with me. - Who the heck are you?
我刚才才告诉你...算了 听我讲 我来自未来
I just told you... Listen. I'm from the future.
- 你个李鬼还敢指我 - 你先指我的好吗 小老弟
- How dare you point at me! - You were pointing first.
- 用手指指人很不礼貌的 - 你现在就很不礼貌
- It's rude to point. - You're being very rude.
谁先指的谁啊
Which one pointed first?
很显然 是蜘蛛侠先动手指的
Spider- Man pointed first. Obviously.
- 你现在就在指着我 - 我没有在指你
- You're pointing at me right now. - I'm not pointing.
瞧你的手指摆哪呢
Look at your finger.
我在指出你在指我 这哪跟哪啊 完全两码子事
I'm pointing out your pointing, which is different.
你没见过真正指人是什么样呢
You haven't seen pointing.
你居然敢一边指着我一遍指责我在指...
You're accusing me of pointing while you're...!